<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<plecoflash formatversion="2" creator="Pleco User -1" generator="Pleco 2.0 Flashcard Exporter" platform="Android" created="1579703652">
    <cards>
        <card language="chinese">
            <entry>
                <headword charset="sc">没</headword>
                <headword charset="tc">沒</headword>
                <pron type="hypy" tones="numbers">mei2</pron>
                <defn>verb colloquial 1 not have 没病 méi bìng in good health; not bad 没朋友 méi péngyou have no friends 2 there is not; be without 用没了。 Yòng méi le. It’s all used up. 票卖没了。 Piào mài méi le. The tickets are all sold out. 这儿没人。 Zhèr méi rén. There’s nobody here. 钢笔没水了。 gāngbǐ méi shuǐ le. The pen has run dry. 3 be not as ... as 我没你高。 Wǒ méi nǐ gāo. I’m not so tall as you. 谁都没他会说话。 Shuí dōu méi tā huì shuōhuà. No one is more eloquent than him. 4 less than; not more than 他去了没多大工夫。 Tā qù le méi duō dà gōngfu. He wasn’t gone for long. 
adverb colloquial have not; did not 你买了吗？——没买。 Nǐ mǎi le ma？ —— méi mǎi. Did you buy it? — No, I didn’t. 银行昨天没开门。 Yínháng zuótiān méi kāimén. The bank was closed yesterday.</defn>
            </entry>
            <dictref dictid="PACE" entryid="26606080"/>
            <catassign category="100/Freq80"/>
        </card>
        <card language="chinese">
            <entry>
                <headword charset="sc">本</headword>
                <headword charset="tc">本</headword>
                <pron type="hypy" tones="numbers">ben3</pron>
                <defn>noun 1 the root or stem of a plant 水有源, 木有本。 Shuǐ yǒu yuán, mù yǒu běn. A stream has its source; a tree its roots. 2 foundation; basis; origin (opp. 末) 健康是幸福生活之本。 Jiànkāng shì xìngfú shēnghuó zhī běn. Health is fundamental to a happy life. 3 capital; principal 还本付息 huánběnfùxī pay back the principal plus interest 赔本儿买卖 Péi běn r mǎimai losing business 
verb be based on 每句话都有所本。 Měi jù huà dōu yǒusuǒ běn. Every statement is well-founded. 
adjective 1 major; central See 17399296本部ben3bu4本部 2 original; intrinsic See 17415680本性ben3xing4本性 
adverb originally; at first 我本不想去 wǒ běn bù xiǎng qù Originally I didn&apos;t want to go. 
pronoun 1 oneself; one&apos;s own work 本单位 běn dānwèi one’s own work unit 2 current; this; present 本周 běnzhōu this week; the current week 本决议 běn juéyì this resolution 
preposition according to; in line with 本有关规定执行 běn yǒuguān guīdìng zhíxíng act according to the relevant rules and regulations 
noun 1 book 账本 zhàngběn account book; ledger 笔记本 bǐjìběn notebook 户口本 hùkǒuběn residence registration booklet 日记本 rìjìběn diary 2 manuscript; script; copy 抄本 chāoběn hand-copied book; transcript 剧本 jùběn script 影印本 yǐngyìnběn photocopy 3 edition; version 普及本 pǔjíběn popular edition 善本 shànběn valuable edition 4 colloquial licence; diploma; certificate 考本 kǎoběn take tests for a driver’s licence; take driving tests 
measure word [for books, parts of a serial, etc.] 两本书 Liǎng běn shū two books 这部电影有十二本。 Zhè bù diànyǐng yǒu shí&apos;èr běn. This is a twelve-reel film.</defn>
            </entry>
            <dictref dictid="PACE" entryid="17398016"/>
            <catassign category="HSK 2012-2018/Level 1"/>
            <catassign category="100/Freq100"/>
        </card>
        <card language="chinese">
            <entry>
                <headword charset="sc">大</headword>
                <headword charset="tc">大</headword>
                <pron type="hypy" tones="numbers">da4</pron>
                <defn>adjective 1 big; large; great (opp. 小) 大城市 dà chéngshì big city 这张照片不够大。 Zhè zhāng zhàopiàn bù gòu dà. The picture isn’t large enough. 2 heavy (rain, etc.); strong (wind, etc.) (opp. 小) 风好大。 Fēng hǎo dà. It’s blowing hard. 雪下得很大。 Xuě xià de hěn dà. The snow is falling heavily. 3 loud (opp. 小) 把收音机开大点儿。 bǎ shōuyīnjī kāi dà diǎnr. Turn the radio up a bit louder. 4 general; main; major 大反攻 dà fǎngōng general counteroffensive 大马路 dàmǎlù main street 大手术 dàshǒushù major operation 大问题 dà wèntí major issue; big problem 5 (of age, usu. of a child or youth) old (opp. 小) 他(已经)很大了。 Tā hěn dà le. He’s grown up. 这孩子多大了？ Zhè háizi duō dà le? How old is this child? 6 eldest 大房 dàfáng senior branch of a family 大哥 Dàgē eldest brother 7 courteous your 大札 dàzhá your letter 大作 dàzuò your writing 
adverb 1 greatly; fully 大笑 dàxiào laugh heartily 大长中国人民的志气 Dà zhǎng Zhōngguó rénmín de zhìqi greatly heighten the morale of the Chinese people 天已大亮。 Tiān yǐ dà liàng. It’s already broad daylight. 2 in a big way; on a big (or large) scale; with all-out efforts; vigorously 大删大改 Dà shān dà gǎi do a thorough job in revising 3 [before a time word, etc. to show emphasis] 大清早 dàqīngzǎo early in the morning 
noun dialect 1 father 2 father&apos;s brother; uncle</defn>
            </entry>
            <dictref dictid="PACE" entryid="19389440"/>
            <catassign category="HSK 2012-2018/Level 1"/>
            <catassign category="100/Freq20"/>
        </card>
        <card language="chinese">
            <entry>
                <headword charset="sc">的</headword>
                <headword charset="tc">的</headword>
                <pron type="hypy" tones="numbers">de5</pron>
                <defn>auxiliary 1 [after an attribute] 铁的纪律 tiě de jìlǜ iron discipline 我的母亲 wǒ de mǔqin my mother 别开他的玩笑了。 Bié kāi tā de wánxiào le. Don’t make fun of him. 2 [forming a noun phrase or nominal expression] 打字的 dǎzì de typist 我爱吃辣的。 Wǒ ài chī là de. I like spicy food. 他说他的, 我干我的。 Tā shuō tā de, wǒ gàn wǒ de. Let him say what he likes; I’ll just get on with my work. 3 [after a verb or between a verb and its object to stress an element of the sentence] 谁买的票？ Shuí mǎi de piào? Who bought the tickets? 他是昨天进的城。 Tā shì zuótiān jìn de chéng. He went to town yesterday. 你嗓子怎么哑了？——唱的。 Nǐ sǎngzi zěnme yā le？ —— chàng de. Why are you so hoarse? — From singing. 4 [at the end of a declarative sentence for emphasis] 你们这两天真够辛苦的。 Nǐmen zhè liǎng tiān zhēn gòu xīnkǔ de. You’ve really been working hard the past few days. 5 [expressing the idea of “of that kind”] 针头线脑的 Zhēntóu-xiànnǎo de things like needles and threads 
VARIANT OF 19760640得de2得 dé 3 verb fit; suit</defn>
            </entry>
            <dictref dictid="PACE" entryid="19779584"/>
            <catassign category="HSK 2012-2018/Level 1"/>
            <catassign category="100/Freq10"/>
        </card>
        <card language="chinese">
            <entry>
                <headword charset="sc">都</headword>
                <headword charset="tc">都</headword>
                <pron type="hypy" tones="numbers">dou1</pron>
                <defn>adverb 1 all 大家都到了吗？ Dàjiā dōu dào le ma？ Is everybody here? 什么都行。 Shénme dōu xíng. Anything will do. 我父母都不在了。 Wǒ fùmǔ dōu bù zài le. My parents are both deceased. 2 [with 是 to show the cause] 都是你, 把他灌成这样。 Dōu shì nǐ, bǎ tā guàn chéng zhèyàng. It’s all your fault making him drunk. 都是你老磨蹭, 害得我们迟到了。 Dōu shì nǐ lǎo móceng, hài de wǒmen chídào le. It is because you dawdled that we were late. 3 even 今天天气真怪, 中午比早晨都冷。 Jīntiān tiānqì zhēn guài, zhōngwǔ bǐ zǎochen dōu lěng. What strange weather, it’s colder at noon than early in the morning! 连他都不知道。 Lián tā dōu bù zhīdao. Even he doesn’t know. 4 already 他都八十岁了, 身子骨还那么硬朗。 Tā dōu bāshí suì le, shēnzi gǔ hái nàme yìnglang. He’s already eighty but still going strong.</defn>
            </entry>
            <dictref dictid="PACE" entryid="20234496"/>
            <catassign category="HSK 2012-2018/Level 1"/>
            <catassign category="100/Freq70"/>
        </card>
        <card language="chinese">
            <entry>
                <headword charset="sc">多</headword>
                <headword charset="tc">多</headword>
                <pron type="hypy" tones="numbers">duo1</pron>
                <defn>adjective 1 many; much; more (opp. 少, 寡) 很多人 hěn duō rén many people 多思。 Duō sī. Think more. 人多议论多。 Rén duō yìlùn duō. More people mean more ideas. 这样简单多了。 Zhèyàng jiǎndān duō le. This is much simpler. 要办的事情很多。 Yào bàn de shìqing hěn duō. There are many things to do. 他多喝了一点儿 (= 喝多了一点儿)。 tā duō hē le yīdiǎnr . He’s had a drop too much. 我在那儿多住了几天。 Wǒ zài nàr duō zhù le jǐ tiān. I stayed there a few days longer. 时间紧迫, 我不能多考虑。 Shíjiān jǐnpò, wǒ bù néng duō kǎolǜ. Time is running out so I can’t give it much thought. 我们比原计划多打了十口井。 Wǒmen bǐ yuán jìhuà duō dǎ le shí kǒu jǐng. We have sunk ten more wells than planned. 昨天很热, 今天凉快多了。 Zuótiān hěn rè, jīntiān liángkuai duō le. It was quite hot yesterday but today it’s a lot cooler. 2 excessive 多疑 duōyí suspicious; distrusting 
adverb over a specified amount; and more 十多斤 shí duō jīn a dozen or more jin 十斤多 shí jīn duō over ten jin 六十多岁 liùshí duō suì over sixty years old 三个多月 sān ge duō yuè over three months; three months and more 一百多个人 yībǎi duō ge rén more than 100 people 全书一千多页。 Quánshū yīqiān duō yè. It’s a book of 1,000-odd pages. 
verb 1 have (a specified amount) more or too much (opp. 少) 班上多了三个新同学。 Bān shàng duō le sān ge xīn tóngxué. There are three more new students in the class. 这个句子多了一个词。 zhège jùziduō le yī ge cí. There is one word too many in this sentence. 2 have sth. in abundance 南方多水, 利于灌溉。 Nánfāng duō shuǐ, lìyú guàngài. Irrigation is easy in the South because of the abundance of water. 这里春天多风, 夏天多雨。 Zhèlǐ chūntiān duō fēng, xiàtiān duō yǔ. Here we have a lot of wind in spring and a lot of rain in summer. 
adverb 1 [in questions] to what extent 他多大年纪了？ Tā duō dà niánjì le？ How old is he? 天安门有多高？ Tiān&apos;ānmén yǒu duō gāo？ How high is Tian’anmen? 多厚的木板才能做桌面呢？ Duō hòu de mùbǎn cái néng zuò zhuōmiàn ne？ How thick must a wooden plank be to make a table top? 2 [in exclamations] to what an extent 看她多漂亮！ Kàn tā duō piàoliang! Look how pretty she is! 这天儿多闷哪！ Zhètiānr duō mēn nǎ! What stuffy weather! 3 to an unspecified extent 有多大劲儿使多大劲儿。 Yǒu duō dà jìnr shǐ duō dà jìnr. Use out all the strength you have. 走出不多远, 他又回来了。 Zǒu chū bù duō yuǎn, tā yòu huílai le. He turned back before going far. 多复杂的算术题他都能做出来。 Duō fùzá de suànshù tí tā dōu néng zuò chūlai. He can figure out any arithmetic problem, no matter how complicated.</defn>
            </entry>
            <dictref dictid="PACE" entryid="20426752"/>
            <catassign category="HSK 2012-2018/Level 1"/>
            <catassign category="100/Freq70"/>
        </card>
        <card language="chinese">
            <entry>
                <headword charset="sc">个</headword>
                <headword charset="tc">個</headword>
                <pron type="hypy" tones="numbers">ge4</pron>
                <defn>measure word 1 [before nouns without special measure words of their own] 两个星期 liǎng gè xīngqī two weeks; a fortnight 三个苹果 sān gè píngguǒ three apples 一个故事 yī gè gùshi a story 2 [used to replace certain measure words] 一个工厂 Yī gè gōngchǎng a factory 一个学校 yī gè xuéxiào a school 3 [before an approximate number] 哥儿俩也不过差个两三岁。 Gērliǎ yě bùguò chà gè liǎng sān suì. There’sonly a two or three years difference between the two brothers. 他每星期来个一两趟。 Tā měi xīngqī lái gè yī, liǎng tàng. He comes here once or twice every week. 4 [between a verb and its object] 洗个澡 Xǐ gè zǎo have a bath 睡个好觉 shuì gè hǎo jiào have a good sleep 5 [between a verb and its complement] 忙个不停 máng gè bù tíng be as busy as a bee 雨下个不停。 Yǔ xià gè bù tíng. It kept raining. 6 [after 一 in certain phrases to indicate suddenness] 他一个箭步窜了上去。 Tā yī gè jiànbù cuàn le shàngqu. With a sudden big stride, he leapt forward. 一个失手我把茶杯打了。 yī gè shīshǒu wǒ bǎ chábēi dǎ le. I accidentally dropped the cup and broke it. 
adjective 1 individual See 21603328个体ge4ti3个体 2 colloquial of strong character 这人个得很。 Zhè rén gè de hěn. The man is really eccentric. 
affix 1 [after 些] 那些个花儿 Nàxiē gè huā&apos;ér all those flowers 这些个书哪能看完？ Zhèxiē gè shū nǎ néng kàn wán？ How can I finish reading so many books? 2 dialect [after 昨儿, 今儿, 明儿, etc.] 明儿个 míngrgè tomorrow</defn>
            </entry>
            <dictref dictid="PACE" entryid="21600000"/>
            <catassign category="HSK 2012-2018/Level 1"/>
            <catassign category="100/Freq20"/>
        </card>
        <card language="chinese">
            <entry>
                <headword charset="sc">好</headword>
                <headword charset="tc">好</headword>
                <pron type="hypy" tones="numbers">hao3</pron>
                <defn>adjective 1 good; fine; nice (opp. 坏) 好人 hǎorén nice person 祖国的好儿子 Zǔguó de hǎo érzi worthy (or fine) son of our country 庄稼长得真好。 Zhuāngjia zhǎng de zhēn hǎo. The crops are growing well. 2 friendly; kind 好朋友 Hǎo péngyou good (or great) friend 他们对我真好。 Tāmen duì wǒ zhēn hǎo. They are really kind to me. 俩孩子又好了。 Liǎ háizi yòu hǎo le. The two children are friends again. 3 be in good health; get well 你好哇！ Nǐ hǎo wa! How are you? 我的病好了。 Wǒ de bìng hǎo le. I’m well (or all right) now. 4 be ready; done 饭好了。 Fàn hǎo le. The food (or rice) is ready. 5 [after verbs to indicate finishing or finishing satisfactorily] 我把他的病治好了。 Wǒ bǎ tā de bìng zhì hǎo le. I cured his illness. 这件事他做不好。 Zhè jiàn shì tā zuò bù hǎo. He can’t do this job well. 坐好吧, 要开会了。 Zuò hǎo ba, yào kāihuì le. Take your seats, please. The meeting is going to begin. 6 [before verbs to denote what is satisfying] good; easy 好吃 hǎochī good to eat—delicious 暖瓶放在这儿好拿。 Nuǎnpíng fàng zài zhèr hǎo ná. It’s handy to have the thermos here. 这本书可不好买。 Zhè běn shū kě bù hǎo mǎi. This book is not easily available. 这个问题好回答。 Zhège wèntí hǎo huídá. This question is easy to answer. 7 [at the beginning of a sentence or clause, to express agreement, disapproval, surprise, etc.] 好, 就这么办。 Hǎo, jiù zhème bàn. OK, it’s settled. 好了, 不要再说了。 Hǎo le, bùyào zài shuō le. All right, no need to say any more. 好！ 那得多少钱！ Hǎo! Nà dé duōshao qián! Gosh! How much money will that cost! 好,  这下可麻烦了。 Hǎo, zhè xià kě máfan le. Well, we’re in for trouble now. 
adverb 1 [before adjectives with exclamatory force] very; quite; so 好大的工程！ Hǎo dà de gōngchéng! What a huge project! 你好大胆子。 Nǐ hǎo dà dǎnzi. You are so daring. 2 dialect [before adjectives in the same way as 多] to what extent; how 火车站离这儿好远？ Huǒchēzhàn lí zhèr hǎo yuǎn？ How far is the railway station from here? 3 [before indefinite time or numbers] quite 好半天 hǎobàntiān quite a while 好几个 hǎojǐgè quite a few 好几天 hǎojǐtiān quite a few days 
verb produce favourable effects 这事可好了他了。 Zhè shì kě hǎo le tā le. This will benefit him. 
auxiliary 1 the better to; in order to; so that 把她的地址告诉我, 我好找她。 Bǎ tā de dìzhǐ gàosu wǒ, wǒ hǎo zhǎo tā. Tell me her address so that I can go and see her. 今儿早点睡, 明儿好早起赶火车。 Jīnr zǎodiǎn shuì, míngr hǎo zǎoqǐ gǎn huǒchē. Let’s turn in early, so as to get up early tomorrow to catch the train. 2 dialect may; can; should 我好进来吗？ Wǒ hǎo jìnlai ma？ May I come in? 时间不早了, 你好走了。 Shíjiān bù zǎo le, nǐhǎo zǒu le. It’s getting late. You ought to get going.</defn>
            </entry>
            <dictref dictid="PACE" entryid="22429952"/>
            <catassign category="HSK 2012-2018/Level 1"/>
            <catassign category="100/Freq90"/>
        </card>
        <card language="chinese">
            <entry>
                <headword charset="sc">和</headword>
                <headword charset="tc">和</headword>
                <pron type="hypy" tones="numbers">he2</pron>
                <defn>adjective 1 gentle; mild; kind 温和 wēnhé mild; temperate 2 harmonious; on good terms 和为贵。 Hé wéi guì. Harmony is what matters. 
noun 1 peace 2 (Hé) a surname 
verb sports draw; tie 那盘棋和了。 Nà pán qí hé le. That game of chess ended in a draw. 
conjunction and 我和你 Wǒ hé nǐ you and I 工人和农民 Gōngrén hé nóngmín workers and peasants 
preposition [indicating relationship, comparison, etc.] 和这件事没有关系 Hé zhè jiàn shì méiyǒu guānxi have nothing to do with the matter; bear no relation to it 他和我一样高。 Tā hé wǒ yīyàng gāo. He’s as tall as I. 
noun mathematics sum 两数之和 liǎng shù zhī hé the sum of the two numbers 
verb together with See 22529280和盘托出he2pan2tuo1chu1和盘托出 
noun Japan 汉和词典 hàn hé cídiǎn Chinese-Japanese dictionary</defn>
            </entry>
            <dictref dictid="PACE" entryid="22523392"/>
            <catassign category="HSK 2012-2018/Level 1"/>
            <catassign category="100/Freq20"/>
        </card>
        <card language="chinese">
            <entry>
                <headword charset="sc">会</headword>
                <headword charset="tc">會</headword>
                <pron type="hypy" tones="numbers">hui4</pron>
                <defn>noun 1 meeting; gathering; party; get-together; conference 报告会 bàogàohuì public lecture 研讨会 yántǎohuì seminar 2 association; society; union 帮会 bānghuì secret soceity 协会 xiéhuì association 3 temple fair 庙会 miàohuì temple fair 4 association of worshippers 香会 xiānghuì company of Buddhist pilgrims 5 revolving credit association (people who regularly contribute to a common fund and draw from it by turns) 6 chief city; capital 都会 dūhuì metropolis 7 literary opportunity; occasion 适逢其会 shìféngqíhuì happen to be present at the right moment 
verb 1 get together; assemble 聚会 jùhuì meet; get together 2 meet; see 昨天我没有会着他。 Zuótiān wǒ méiyǒu huì zhe tā. I didn’t see him yesterday. 3 literary happen to 会有客来。 Huì yǒu kè lái. A visitor happened to come by. 4 literary should; ought to 
verb 1 understand; grasp 误会 wùhuì misunderstand 2 know 他还会两出京戏。 Tā hái huì liǎng chū Jīngxì. He knows a few airs of Beijing opera. 我会英语, 不会日语。 Wǒ huì Yīngyǔ, bù huì Rìyǔ. I know English but not Japanese. 3 can; be able to 会滑冰 Huì huábīng can skate 这孩子刚会走路, 还不大会说话。 Zhè háizi gāng huì zǒulù, hái bù dà huì shuōhuà. The infant has just learnt to walk but not to speak yet. 4 excel at; be good at; be skillful in 会修钟表 huì xiū zhōngbiǎo skilled in repairing clocks and watches 很会这一套 hěn huì zhè yī tào be a past master of this sort of game 5 be likely to; be sure to 他会来的。 Tā huì lái de. He’s sure to come. 他会在家吗？ Tā huì zài jiā ma？ Is he likely to be at home? 没想到(事情)会这么顺利。 méi xiǎngdào huì zhème shùnlì. I didn’t expect things to go so smoothly. 
verb pay (or foot) a bill 饭钱我会过了。 Fàn qián wǒ huì guò le. I’ve paid for the meal. 
noun colloquial moment 来了一会儿了 Lái le yī huì r le have been here for a while</defn>
            </entry>
            <dictref dictid="PACE" entryid="23167488"/>
            <catassign category="HSK 2012-2018/Level 1"/>
            <catassign category="100/Freq40"/>
        </card>
        <card language="chinese">
            <entry>
                <headword charset="sc">开</headword>
                <headword charset="tc">開</headword>
                <pron type="hypy" tones="numbers">kai1</pron>
                <defn>verb 1 open 开锁 kāisuǒ open a lock; unlock 门开了。 Mén kāi le. The door opened. 2 make an opening; open up 墙上开了个窗口。 Qiáng shàng kāi le ge chuāngkǒu. A window was made in the wall. 3 openout; come loose 4 produce flowers; bloom 花都开了。 Huā dōu kāi le. The flowers are all blooming. 扣儿开了。 Kòur kāi le. The knot has come untied. 两块木板没粘好, 又开了。 Liǎng kuài mùbǎn méi zhān hǎo, yòu kāi le. The two pieces of wood were not glued together properly. They have come loose again. 5 (of a frozen river) thaw out 河开了。 hé kāi le. The river thawed (or is open). 6 lift (a ban, restriction, etc.) See 24802048开禁kai1jin4开禁 7 start; operate (a machine, car, ship, plane, etc.) 8 turn on (a light, radio, TV, etc.); switch on 开灯 kāidēng turn on a light 开飞机 kāi fēijī fly (or pilot) an airplane 开机器 Kāi jīqì operate (or run) a machine 开汽车 kāi qìchē drive a car 把汽船开到对岸去。 Bǎ qìchuán kāi dào duì&apos;àn qù. Steer the motorboat over to the opposite bank. 9 (of a train, bus, ship, etc.) leave; start 火车几点开？ Huǒchē jǐ diǎn kāi？ What time does the train leave? 10 (of troops) set out; move 昨天开来了两团人, 今天又开走了。 Zuótiān kāi lái le liǎng tuán rén, jīntiān yòu kāi zǒu le. Two regiments came yesterday and set off today. 11 start or run (a factory, school, store, etc.); set up; open 开茶馆 kāi cháguǎn run a teahouse 开工厂 Kāi gōngchǎng set up a factory 百货店就开在十字路口。 Bǎihuòdiàn jiù kāi zài shízì lùkǒu. The department store is located at the intersection. 12 (of an institute, organization, etc.) open to the public See 64455907开馆kai1guan3开馆 / 13 (of film shooting, auction, etc.) begin; start See 24814080开拍kai1pai1开拍 / 14 hold (a meeting, exhibition, etc.) 开运动会 Kāi yùndònghuì hold a sports meet 舞会开了一夜。 Wǔhuì kāi le yī yè. The dance lasted all night. 15 make a list of; write out; prescribe 开支票 kāi zhīpiào write out a cheque 开介绍信 kāi jièshàoxìn write a letter of introduction 开信用证 kāi xìnyòngzhèng issue a credit 医生给我开了些药片。 Yīshēng gěi wǒ kāi le xiē yàopiàn. The doctor prescribed some pills for me. 16 pay (wages, fares, etc.) 开工资 kāi gōngzī pay wages 17 dialect fire (an employee); fire out; give sb. the sack; kick out 这个公司刚刚开了几个人。 zhège gōngsī gānggāng kāi le jǐ gèrén. The company has just fired several of its employees. 18 boil 水开了。 Shuǐ kāi le. The water is boiling. 19 colloquial eat up 他把包子都开了。 Tā bǎ bāozi dōu kāi le. He ate up all the stuffed buns. 
adjective open 开循环 kāi xúnhuán open cycle 
measure word 1 [expressing a ratio between two things considered as parts of a whole which is 10] 二八开 Èrbā kāi 2:8 大家认为他的功过是三七开。 Dàjiā rènwéi tā de gōng-guò shì sānqī kāi. The general assessment of his work is 70% achievements and 30% mistakes. 2 printing division of standard size printing paper 对开 duìkāi folio 四开 sìkāi quarto 
measure word 1 transliteration carat (ct) 十四开金 14- Shísì kāi jīn carat gold 2 abbreviation VARIANT OF 64450787开尔文kai1er3wen2开尔文 physics degree Kelvin; kelvin (K)</defn>
            </entry>
            <dictref dictid="PACE" entryid="24781056"/>
            <catassign category="HSK 2012-2018/Level 1"/>
            <catassign category="100/Freq100"/>
        </card>
        <card language="chinese">
            <entry>
                <headword charset="sc">看</headword>
                <headword charset="tc">看</headword>
                <pron type="hypy" tones="numbers">kan4</pron>
                <defn>verb 1 see; look at; watch 看电视 kàn diànshì watch TV 看电影 kàn diànyǐng see a film; go to the movies 看球赛 kàn qiú sài watch a ball game 看演出 kàn yǎnchū attend a performance 看展览 kàn zhǎnlǎn visit an exhibition 2 read (silently) 看报 kànbào read a newspaper 看谱 kànpǔ read music score 看书 kànshū read (a book) 3 think; consider; judge 看清形势 kàn qīng xíngshì make a correct appraisal of the situation 全面地看问题 quánmiàn de kàn wèntí look at (or approach) an issue from all angles 你看她这个人可靠吗？ Nǐ kàn tā zhège rén kěkào ma？ Do you think she’s reliable? 你对这件事怎么看？ Nǐ duì zhè jiàn shì zěnme kàn？ What’s your view on this matter? 4 look upon; regard 把公众的利益看得高于一切 bǎ gōngzhòng de lìyì kàn de gāoyú yīqiè put the interests of the public above all else 5 see (or consult) (a doctor); treat (a patient or an illness) 李大夫把她的肺炎看好了。 Lǐ dàifu bǎ tā de fèiyán kàn hǎo le. Dr. Li has cured her of pneumonia. 有病就该去看。 Yǒu bìng jiù gāi qù kàn. You ought to go and see a doctor when you are ill. 6 look after 衣帽自看。 Yī-mào zì kàn. Take care of your own hats and coats. 7 call on; visit; see 我明天去看他。 Wǒ míngtiān qù kàn tā. I’ll go and see him tomorrow. 有空我来看你。 Yǒukòng wǒ lái kàn nǐ. I’lldrop in on you when I have time. 8 depend on; rely on; fall back on 我们明天是不是出游, 得看天气。 wǒmen míngtiān shìbushì chūyóu, děikàn tiānqì. Whether we’ll go on a sightseeing trip tomorrow will depend on the weather. 9 mind; watch out 别跑这么快！看摔着！ Bié pǎo zhème kuài! Kàn shuāi zhe! Don’t run so fast! Mind you don’t fall. 10 [before some verbs or adjectives] tend to; be expected See 24863488看跌kan4die1看跌 
auxiliary 1 [after a reduplicated verb or a verb phrase] try and see (what happens) 试试看 shìshikàn have a try 等一等看 děng yī děng kàn wait and see 尝尝看。 Chángchang kàn. Just taste this. 2 [in exclamations to express surprise or rebuke, esp. in the phrase 看你 or 你看你] 看你, 水都烧干了。 Kàn nǐ, shuǐ dōu shāo gān le. Look what you’ve done! The water has all boiled away. 你看你！怎么满头大汗啊！ Nǐ kàn nǐ! Zěnme mǎntóudàhàn a! Look at yourself! How come you’re bathed in sweat!</defn>
            </entry>
            <dictref dictid="PACE" entryid="24859392"/>
            <catassign category="HSK 2012-2018/Level 1"/>
            <catassign category="100/Freq80"/>
        </card>
        <card language="chinese">
            <entry>
                <headword charset="sc">来</headword>
                <headword charset="tc">來</headword>
                <pron type="hypy" tones="numbers">lai2</pron>
                <defn>verb 1 come (to); arrive 来得不巧 Láide bùqiǎo come at an unsuitable time (or moment) 来得正好 láide zhènghǎo come in good time; come just at the right time 就来！ jiù lái! I’m coming. 快来！ Kuài lái! Come along! 来客人了。 Lái kèren le. We have a guest. 客人来了。 Kèren lái le. The guests are here. 他今天来过两次。 Tā jīntiān lái guò liǎng cì. He came twice today. 他已经来了。 Tā yǐjinglái le. He has already come. 她明天来北京。 Tā míngtiān lái Běijīng. She is coming to Beijing tomorrow. 有空来玩。 Yǒukòng lái wán. Come round when you have time. 远处来了一条小船。 Yuǎnchù lái le yī tiáo xiǎochuán. A small boat came into view in the distance. 2 cause to come; happen; crop up; take place 问题来了。 Wèntí lái le. A problem has come up. 这事儿怎么来的？ Zhè shìr zěnme lái de？ How did it come about? 3 obtain; get 这差事来得不容易。 Zhè chāishilái de bù róngyì. This job is hard to come by. 4 [as a substitute for some other verb] 来份糖醋鱼。 lái fèn tángcùyú. A sweet-and-sour fish, please. 你来块糖。 Nǐ lái kuài táng. Have some candy. 再来一个！ Zàilái yī ge! [call for another performance] Encore! 慢慢儿来, 别忙。 Mànmànr lái, bié máng. Take it easy. No hurry. 我累了, 你来吧。 Wǒ lèi le, nǐ lái ba. I’m tired. Why don’t you take over (or carry on). 咱们来一盘棋。 Zánmenlái yī pán qí. Let’s have a game of chess. 你歇歇, 让我来吧。 Nǐ xiēxie, ràng wǒ lái ba. You take a rest. Let me do it. 我自己来吧, 别客气。 Wǒ zìjǐ lái ba, bié kèqi. Please don’t bother. I’ll do it myself. 我们打篮球, 你来不来？ Wǒmen dǎ lánqiú, nǐ lái bù lái？ We’re going to play basketball. Will you join in? 5 [with 得 or 不, indicating possibility or impossibility, capability or incapability] 上海话我说不来。 Shànghǎi huà wǒ shuō bù lái. I don’t speak Shanghai dialect. 我吃不来四川菜。 Wǒ chī bù lái Sìchuān cài. I can’t get used to Sichuan cuisine. 西餐我吃得来。 Xīcān wǒ chī de lái. Western food suits me all right. 这道题我做不来。 Zhè dào tí wǒ zuò bù lái. I can’t do this problem. 这个歌我唱得来。 Zhège gē wǒ chàng de lái. I can sing this song. 6 [before a verb, indicating an intended or suggested action] 你来试试。 Nǐ lái shìshi. Have a try. 我来说两句。 Wǒ láishuō liǎng jù. Let me say a few words. 大家来想办法。 Dàjiā lái xiǎng bànfǎ. Let’s think of a way (to solve the problem). or Let’s put our heads together and see how to do it. 7 [after a verb or verbal expression] come in order to 他回家探亲来了。 Tā huíjiā tànqīn lái le. He’s come home to see his parents. 我们道喜来了。 Wǒmen dàoxǐ lái le. We’ve come to congratulate you (or offer our congratulations). 8 [between two verbs or verbal expressions to indicate the purpose of the former] in order to 想办法来解决问题 Xiǎng bànfǎ lái jiějué wèntí think of a way to solve the problem 你又能用什么理由来说服他呢？ Nǐ yòu néng yòng shénme lǐyóu lái shuōfú tā ne？ And what arguments can you use to convince him? 9 (of electricity, tap water, gas, etc.) be on again 来电了。 lái diàn le. The power is on again. 来水了。 lái shuǐ le. There’s running water again. 
auxiliary 1 colloquial [at the end of a sentence to indicate what has happened in the past, same as 来着] 你这是何苦来？ Nǐ zhè shì hékǔlái? Why did you do that (and made yourself unhappy)? 2 [after a time expression, indicating a period of time that extends from the past up to the present] ever since 几天来 jǐ tiān lái for the last few days 一年来 yī nián lái during the past year 3 [after a round number or after a numeral plus a measure] approximately; about; around; round 二十来个 èrshí lái ge about 20 四十来岁 sìshí lái suì round 40 (years old) 十来块钱 shí lái kuài qián somewhere over 10 yuan 两米来高 liǎng mǐ lái gāo about two metres high 百十来里地 bǎishí lái lǐ dì a distance of about 100 li 4 [after the numerals 一, 二, and 三, indicating points in an explanation or argument] 我不要, 一来我不喜欢,  二来我也没钱。 Wǒ bùyào, yī lái wǒ bù xǐhuan, èr lái wǒ yě méiqián. I don’t want it. In the first place, I don’t like it; in the second place, I don’t have the money. 
adjective future; coming; next 来月 láiyuè coming month 
noun (Lái) a surname 
auxiliary [as a syllable filler in folk ballads] 正月里来是新春。 Zhēngyuè lǐ lái shì xīnchūn. The first month is the beginning of spring. 你敲锣来我打鼓。 Nǐ qiāoluó lái wǒ dǎgǔ. You beat the gong while I play the drum.</defn>
            </entry>
            <dictref dictid="PACE" entryid="25308160"/>
            <catassign category="HSK 2012-2018/Level 1"/>
            <catassign category="100/Freq20"/>
        </card>
        <card language="chinese">
            <entry>
                <headword charset="sc">那</headword>
                <headword charset="tc">那</headword>
                <pron type="hypy" tones="numbers">na4</pron>
                <defn>pronoun that 那人 nà rén that man 那时候 nà shíhou at that time 那两棵树 nà liǎng kē shù those two trees 那是 2008 年的事。 Nà shì 1958nián de shì. That was in 2008. 那是谁？ Nà shì shuí？ Who is that? 那是我的错。 Nà shì wǒ de cuò. That was my fault. 我们说这道那的, 不知不觉已到凌晨。 Wǒmen shuō zhè dào nà de, bùzhībùjué yǐ dào língchén. We talked about this and that, and before we knew it, it was almost dawn. 
conjunction then; in that case 那我们就不再等了。 Nà wǒmen jiù bùzài děng le. In that case, we won’t wait any longer. 你要想跟我们一块走, 那就得快点儿。 nǐ yào xiǎng gēn wǒmen yīkuài zǒu, nà jiùděi kuàidianr. If you’re coming with us, you must hurry.</defn>
            </entry>
            <dictref dictid="PACE" entryid="27123712"/>
            <catassign category="HSK 2012-2018/Level 1"/>
            <catassign category="100/Freq40"/>
        </card>
        <card language="chinese">
            <entry>
                <headword charset="sc">能</headword>
                <headword charset="tc">能</headword>
                <pron type="hypy" tones="numbers">neng2</pron>
                <defn>noun 1 ability; capability; skill 技能 jìnéng technical skill 无能 wúnéng incompetent 2 physics energy 波能 bō néng wave energy 风能 fēngnéng wind energy 
verb 1 can do; be able to; be capable of 他好多了, 能下床了。 Tā hǎo duō le, néng xià chuáng le. He’s much better and can get up now. 她一分钟能打七十个字。 Tā yī fēnzhōng néng dǎ qīshí ge zì. She can type 70 words a minute. 我干这个工作能行吗？ Wǒ gàn zhège gōngzuò néng xíng ma？ Am I really fit for the job? 2 possibly 天这么晚了, 他能来吗？ Tiān zhème wǎn le, tā néng lái ma？ It’s already very late. Can he possibly come tonight? 这件事她能一点儿也不知道吗？ Zhè jiàn shì tā néng yīdiǎnr yě bùzhīdào ma? How could she know nothing of this? or Could she be completely in the dark? 3 [between 不…不 to express obligation, certainty or great probability] 不能不 bùnéngbù must; have to; cannot but 4 may; can; have the permission to 这儿能停车吗？——能停(不能停)。 Zhèrnéng tíngchē ma? ——néng tíng. Can we park here?—Yes, you can. (No. Parking is forbidden here.) 
adjective able; capable 她可能呢, 穿的衣服都是自己做的。 Tā kěnéng ne, chuān de yīfu dōu shì zìjǐ zuò de. She’s very clever with her hands and makes all her own clothes.</defn>
            </entry>
            <dictref dictid="PACE" entryid="27275776"/>
            <catassign category="HSK 2012-2018/Level 1"/>
            <catassign category="100/Freq40"/>
        </card>
        <card language="chinese">
            <entry>
                <headword charset="sc">你</headword>
                <headword charset="tc">你</headword>
                <pron type="hypy" tones="numbers">ni3</pron>
                <defn>pronoun 1 you [second person singular] 你爸 nǐ bà your Dad 你带了多少钱？ Nǐ dài le duōshao qián？ How much money do you have on you? 2 you [second person plural] 你方 nǐ fāng your side; you 你校 nǐ xiào your school 3 [referring to any person] you; one; anyone 碰到这么一个人, 你有什么办法？ Pèngdào zhème yī ge rén, nǐ yǒu shénme bànfǎ？ What can you do with a person like that? 4 [with 我 or 他 in parallel structures to indicate several or many people behaving the same way] 三个人你看看我, 我看看你, 谁也不说话。 Sān ge rén nǐ kànkan wǒ,  wǒ kàn kàn nǐ, shuí yě bù shuōhuà. The three of them kept looking at each other without saying a word. 你一言, 我一语, 大家谈得很热闹。 Nǐ yī yán,  wǒ yī yǔ, dàjiā tán de hěn rènao. A lively conversation ensued with everybody joining in.</defn>
            </entry>
            <dictref dictid="PACE" entryid="27304704"/>
            <catassign category="HSK 2012-2018/Level 1"/>
            <catassign category="100/Freq40"/>
        </card>
        <card language="chinese">
            <entry>
                <headword charset="sc">年</headword>
                <headword charset="tc">年</headword>
                <pron type="hypy" tones="numbers">nian2</pron>
                <defn>noun 1 year 年复一年 niánfùyīnián year after year; year in year out 三年 Sān nián three years 2 annual; yearly See 67485923年产量nian2chan3liang4年产量 3 age 年过六十 nián guò liùshí over sixty (years old) 4 period in one&apos;s life 老年 lǎonián old age 童年 tóngnián childhood 5 period in history 近年来 jìnniánlái in recent years 明朝初年 míngzhāo chū nián at the beginning of the Ming Dynasty 6 harvest 丰年 fēngnián rich harvest 7 New Year 过年 guònián celebrate the New Year 8 of or for the New Year See 27329792年货nian2huo4年货 9 archaic relationship between candidates who passed the same imperial examinations See 67505635年兄nian2xiong1年兄;67506403年谊nian2yi4 年谊 10 (Nián) a surname</defn>
            </entry>
            <dictref dictid="PACE" entryid="27323392"/>
            <catassign category="HSK 2012-2018/Level 1"/>
            <catassign category="100/Freq50"/>
        </card>
        <card language="chinese">
            <entry>
                <headword charset="sc">去</headword>
                <headword charset="tc">去</headword>
                <pron type="hypy" tones="numbers">qu4</pron>
                <defn>verb 1 go; go to (a place) 我去。 Wǒ qù. I’ll go. 他已经去了。 Tā yǐjing qù le. He has already gone. 我要去南京了。 Wǒ yào qù Nánjīng le. I’m going to Nanjing. 我想去南京一趟。 Wǒ xiǎng qù Nánjīng yī tàng. I think I’ll take a trip to Nanjing. 我要去车站接人。 Wǒ yào qù chēzhàn jiē rén. I’m going to the station to meet someone. 他去了三天, 还没回来。 Tā qù le sān tiān, hái méi huílai. He’s been away for three days, and hasn’t come back yet. 昨天已经去了三个人。 Zuótiān yǐjing qù le sān ge rén. Three people went there yesterday. 我去了好几趟, 都没碰到他。 Wǒ qù le hǎojǐ tàng, dōu méi pèngdào tā. I went there several times, but never saw him. 2 cause to go; send there 给她去个电话。 Gěi tā qù ge diànhuà. Give her a call. 我给他去过两封信。 Wǒ gěi tā qù guò liǎng fēng xìn. I sent him two letters. 我们只去了个代表。 Wǒmen zhǐ qù le ge dàibiǎo. We only sent a representative. 已经去了一个电报。 Yǐjing qù le yī ge diànbào. A telegram has been sent (to him). 3 remove; get rid of 去头屑 Qù tóu xiè get rid of dandruff 去殖民化 qù zhímínhuà decolonize 去了皮再吃。 Qù le pí zài chī. Peel it before you eat it. 汽油能去油迹。 Qìyóu néng qù yóujì. Gas is good for taking out oil stains. 裙子太长了, 去两公分吧。 qúnzi tài cháng le, qù liǎng gōngfēn ba. The skirt is too long—shorten it by two centimetres. 这句话去几个字就简洁了。 Zhè jù huà qù jǐ ge zì jiù jiǎnjié le. Take out one or two words and the sentence will be more concise. 4 [before and / or after a verb] go in order to; be going to (do sth. there) 咱们去看电影。(= 咱们看电影去。= 咱们去看电影去。) Zánmen qù kàn diànyǐng. (or) zánmen kàn diànyǐng qù. (or) zánmen qù kàn diànyǐng qù. Let’s go to see a movie. 这件事我去办吧。 Zhè jiàn shì wǒ qù bàn ba Let me (go and) arrange this. 你去打水, 我来生炉子。 Nǐ qù dǎ shuǐ, wǒ lái shēng lúzi. You get some water and I’ll light the stove. 你别管, 让他自己去想办法。 Nǐ bié guǎn, ràng tā zìjǐ qù xiǎng bànfǎ. Don’t bother, let him figure it out for himself. 你们去研究研究, 看该怎么办。 Nǐmen qù yánjiū yánjiū, kàn gāi zěnme bàn. Go and make a study of it, and see what’s the best thing to do. 5 [between two verbal expressions, and / or after the second expression] in order to (do sth. there) 用科学的观点去观察事物 Yòng kēxué de guāndiǎn qù guānchá shìwù look at things from a scientific point of view 他回家吃饭去了。 Tā huíjiā chī fàn qù le. He went home to eat. 她上街去买东西了。(= 她上街买东西去了。= 她上街去买东西去了。) Tā shàngjiē qù mǎi dōngxi le. (or) tā shàngjiē mǎi dōngxi qù le. (or) tā shàngjiē qù mǎi dōngxi qù le. She went to the market to do some shopping. 他提了一桶水去浇花。 Tā tí le yī tǒng shuǐ qù jiāo huā. He took a bucket of water to water the flowers. 6 literary be apart from in space or time 去今五十年 Qù jīn wǔshí nián 50 years ago 两地相去四十里。 Liǎng de xiāng qù sìshí lǐ. The two places are 40 li apart. 7 literary depart from; leave See 28802304去国qu4guo2去国 8 euphemistic pass away; die 老太太昨夜去了。 lǎotàitai zuóyè qù le. The old lady died last night. 
noun abbreviation VARIANT OF 28804096去声qu4sheng1去声 1 falling tone (third of the four tones in classical Chinese pronunciation) 2 falling tone (fourth of the four tones in modern standard Chinese pronunciation) 
adjective just gone (or elapsed) 去秋 qù qiū last autumn 去冬今春 qùdōng jīnchūn last winter and this spring 
adverb dialect [with 了 as an intensive complement to certain adjectives with了] very; extremely 他家远了去了。 Tā jiā yuǎn le qù le. His home is far far away. 那片林子可大了去了。 Nà piàn línzi kě dà le qù le. That’s a really huge forest. 他到过的地方多了去了。 Tā dào guò de dìfang duō le qù le. He’s been to a great many places. 
verb play (a part or character) 他在京剧《闹天宫》里去猴王。 Tā zài Jīngjù 《Nào Tiāngōng》 lǐ qù hóuwáng. He played the Monkey King in the Beijing opera Trouble in Heaven.</defn>
            </entry>
            <dictref dictid="PACE" entryid="28800256"/>
            <catassign category="HSK 2012-2018/Level 1"/>
            <catassign category="100/Freq70"/>
        </card>
        <card language="chinese">
            <entry>
                <headword charset="sc">人</headword>
                <headword charset="tc">人</headword>
                <pron type="hypy" tones="numbers">ren2</pron>
                <defn>noun 1 human being; person; people 活人 huórén living person 人对自然界的认识 Rén duì zìránjiè de rènshi man’s knowledge of nature 团结得像一个人 tuánjié de xiàng yī ge rén (of many people) be united as one 来人了。 lái rén le. Someone has come. or There come some people. 他家有几口人？ Tā jiā yǒu jǐ kǒu rén？ How many people are there in his family? 屋里有人吗？ Wū lǐ yǒurén ma？ Is there anyone inside? 2 adult human being 长大成人 zhǎngdà chéngrén grow up into an adult; be grown to manhood 3 other people; other(s) 他待人诚恳。 Tā dàirén chéngkěn. He’s sincere in his dealings with people. 这个座位有人吗？ Zhè ge zuòwèi yǒurén ma？ Is this seat occupied? 自己做错了事, 不应该怪人。 Zìjǐ zuò cuò liǎoshì, bù yīnggāi guàirén. When one has done something wrong one should not blame it on others. 4 [used rhetorically in place of the first personal pronoun, often expressing displeasure] 别小看人！ Bié xiǎokàn rén! Don’t look down on me! 真叫人着急。 Zhēn jiào rén zháojí. It really worries me. 5 person considered as a worker or employee; hand; manpower 人来了吗？ rén lái le ma? Have they come? 我们这里正缺人。 Wǒmen zhèlǐ zhèng quē rén. We are short-handed at the moment. 6 physical, psychological, or moral quality or condition of a given individual; personality 他人很好。 Tā rén hěn hǎo. He’s a very nice man. 这两天我人不太舒服。 Zhè liǎng tiān wǒ rén bù tài shūfu. I haven’t been feeling very well lately. 他人在那儿, 心却想着别的事。 Tā rén zài nàr, xīn què xiǎngzhe bié de shì. He was there all right, but his mind was elsewhere. 7 everybody; each 人各有所喜。 rén gè yǒusuǒ xǐ. Everyone has his liking. 8 [as a suffix] person of certain places, jobs or properties; person engaging in certain activity 四川人 Sìchuān rén native of Sichuan 文化人 wénhuàrén man of letters; intellectual 音乐人 yīnyuèrén musician; person engaging in music 他是你什么人？ Tā shì nǐ shénmerén? What is your relation with him? 9 real person; true man; man of integrity 是人就得说人话。 Shì rén jiùděi shuō rén huà. A real man should talk like a real man. 这是人做的事吗？ Zhè shì rén zuò de shì ma? Can this be the behaviour of a true man?</defn>
            </entry>
            <dictref dictid="PACE" entryid="28962304"/>
            <catassign category="HSK 2012-2018/Level 1"/>
            <catassign category="100/Freq10"/>
        </card>
        <card language="chinese">
            <entry>
                <headword charset="sc">上</headword>
                <headword charset="tc">上</headword>
                <pron type="hypy" tones="numbers">shang4</pron>
                <defn>noun 1 [used alone, esp. in contrast to 下] 上不封顶 shàngbùfēngdǐng impose no ceiling 上至国家主席, 下至普通百姓 shàng zhì guójiā zhǔxí, xià zhì pǔtōng bǎixìng from the state president down to the common people 这个词是旧时下对上的称呼。 Zhège cí shì jiù shíxià duì shàng de chēnghu. This word was used in the old days to address one’s superiors. 2 [after a preposition] 往上看 Wǎng shàng kàn look up (at sth.) 向上拉 xiàng shàng lā pull it up 这头朝上 zhè tóu cháo shàng this side up 向上反映情况 xiàng shàng fǎnyìng qíngkuàng report the situation to the higher-ups 
adjective 1 upper; higher; better; superior 上臂 shàngbì upper arm 上半截 shàngbànjié upper half 在书架的最上一层 zài shūjià de zuì shàng yī céng on the top shelf 中上水平 zhōng shàng shuǐpíng above the average; better than the average 报上一级党委 bào shàng yījí dǎngwěi report to the Party committee immediately above 2 most recent; last; former 上次 shàngcì last time 上两批 shàng liǎng pī the last two groups 上星期四 shàng Xīngqīsì last Thursday 上一季度 shàng yī jìdù the previous quarter 3 first (of sth. divided into two or three parts) 上集 shàngjí Volume I; Part I 上一段 shàng yī duàn the preceding (or above, foregoing) paragraph 上半学期 Shàng bàn xuéqī the first half of the term 二十世纪上半叶 èrshí shìjì shàngbàn yè the first half of the 20th century 这部词典分上, 中, 下三册。 zhè bù cídiǎn fēn shàng, zhōng, xià sān cè. This dictionary is in three volumes, first, second, and third. 4 dated [referring to the emperor] See 29625344上谕shang4yu4上谕 
verb 1 come (or go) up; ascend 上岸 shàng&apos;àn go ashore 上楼 shànglóu go (or come) upstairs; ascend the stairs 上山 shàngshān go (or climb) up a mountain 上一个台阶 shàng yī ge táijiē reach a higher level 溯流而上 sùliú&apos;érshàng sail (or go) upstream 2 get on (a conveyance); mount; board 上船 shàngchuán go aboard a ship; go on board 上飞机 shàng fēijī board a plane 上公共汽车 shàng gōnggòng qìchē get on a bus 3 go to; leave for 上厕所 shàng cèsuǒ go to toilet 你上哪儿？ Nǐ shàng nǎr？ Where are you going? 我明天上南京。 Wǒ míngtiān shàng Nánjīng. I’m leaving for Nanjing tomorrow. 4 be engaged (in work, study, etc.) at a fixed time 上机 shàngjī use the computer 上哨 shàngshào go on sentry 我今天上中班。 Wǒ jīntiān shàng zhōngbān. I’m on the middle shift today. 她上大学了。 Tā shàng dàxué le. She’s now in college. 明天的语文课还上不上？ Míngtiān de yǔwénkè hái shàng bù shàng？ Shall we have our Chinese lessons tomorrow or not? 5 advance; forge ahead; go ahead 见困难就上 Jiàn kùnnan jiù shàng advance where there are difficulties to overcome 快上, 投篮！ Kuài shàng, tóulán! Go ahead. Quick! Shoot! 6 improve; increase 上品种 shàng pǐnzhǒng increase the variety of products 上质量 shàng zhìliàng improve the quality of products 7 sports enter the court (or field) 换人！ 三号下, 四号上。 Huàn rén! Sān hào xià, sì hào shàng. Substitution: Player No. 4 for No. 3. 这一盘你上。 Zhè yī pán nǐ shàng. You play this game. 8 fill; supply; serve 请给我们上点儿茶。 Qǐng gěi wǒmenshàng diǎnr chá. Will you please serve us with some tea? 9 place sth. in position; fix 上刀具 Shàng dāojù fix a cutting tool 我正在上螺丝呢。 Wǒ zhèng zài shàng luósī ne. I’m fixing the screws in place. 10 apply; paint; smear 上药膏 Shàng yàogāo apply ointment 给门窗上漆 gěi mén-chuāng shàng qī paint the door and windows 给机器上油 gěi jīqì shàng yóu oil (or grease) the machine 11 apply for 上牌照 shàngpáizhào apply for a license 12 be put on record; be carried (in a publication) 上《吉尼斯世界纪录大全》 shàng «jí ní sī shìjiè jìlù dàquán» get into the Guinness Book of Records 小王的先进事迹上了电视。 xiǎo wáng de xiānjìnshìjì shàng le diànshì. Xiao Wang’s model deeds have been reported on TV. 13 wind; screw; tighten 表该上了。螺丝没有上紧。 Biǎo gāi shàng le. Luósī méiyǒu shàng jǐn. The watch needs winding. 螺丝没有上紧。 Luósī méiyǒu shàng jǐn. The screw hasn’t been tightened. 14 be up to; as many as 上百辆小汽车 shàng bǎi liàng xiǎoqìchē up to a hundred cars 出席人数已上万。 Chūxí rénshù yǐ shàngwàn. There are as many as ten thousand present. or There is an attendance of 10,000 or so. 15 [ in stage directions] appear on the stage; enter 二战士左上。 Èr zhànshì zuǒ shàng. Enter left two soldiers. 
noun abbreviation shàngshēng 
noun music note of the scale in gongchepu (工尺谱), corresponding to 1 in numbered musical notation</defn>
            </entry>
            <dictref dictid="PACE" entryid="29565952"/>
            <catassign category="HSK 2012-2018/Level 1"/>
            <catassign category="100/Freq20"/>
        </card>
        <card language="chinese">
            <entry>
                <headword charset="sc">是</headword>
                <headword charset="tc">是</headword>
                <pron type="hypy" tones="numbers">shi4</pron>
                <defn>verb 1 [used like “be” before nouns or pronouns to identify, describe or amplify the subject] 我是医生。 wǒ shì yīshēng. I am a doctor. 《阿Ｑ正传》的作者是鲁迅。 《Ā Q Zhèng Zhuàn》 de zuòshì shì Lǔ Xùn. The author of The True Story of Ah Q is Lu Xun. 他真心爱的是你。 Tā zhēn xīn&apos;ài de shì nǐ. You are the girl he truly loves. 她还是一身中学生打扮。 Tā háishì yī shēn zhōngxuéshēng dǎban. She still dresses like a high school girl. 2 [after nouns denoting place or position to express existence] 遍地是鲜花。 Biàn dì shì xiānhuā. The place is covered with flowers. 前面是一片稻田。 Qiánmian shì yī piàn dàotián. There is a stretch of rice fields ahead. 他满身是汗。 Tā mǎnshēn shì hàn. He is sweating all over. 3 [with 的 at the end of the sentence, to indicate category, characteristic, etc.] 我是教书的。 Wǒ shì jiāoshū de. I am a teacher. 那儿的房屋是木头的。 Nàr de fángwū shì mùtou de. The houses there are built of wood. 马路边净是看热闹的。 Mǎlù biān jìng shì kàn rènao de. The street was crowded with people watching the excitement. 4 [emphasizing a certain part of a sentence] a [before the subject to stress it] 是谁告诉你的？ Shì shuí gàosu nǐ de？ Who told you? 花瓶是我妹妹摔破的。 Huāpíng shì wǒ mèimei shuāi pò de. It was my sister who broke the vase. b [after a verb or adjective plus 的, to stress the predicate] 说的正是你。 Shuō de zhèngshì nǐ. It’s you we are talking about. 可惜的是浪费了这么多时间。 Kěxī deshì làngfèi le zhème duō shíjiān. It’s a pity we’ve wasted so much time. 麻烦的是他生病来不了。 Máfan de shì tā shēngbìng láibuliǎo. The trouble is he’s taken ill and can’t come. c [before the object, adverbial, etc. to be stressed] 我是专程去看老王的。 Wǒ shì zhuānchéng qù kàn lǎo wáng de. I made a special trip to see Lao Wang. 他们看的是话剧, 不是电影。 Tāmen kàn de shì huàjù, bù shì diànyǐng. They went to see a play, not a film. or What they saw was a play, not a film. 好好的一次郊游搞成这样子, 都是你！ Hǎo hǎo de yī cì jiāoyóu gǎo chéng zhè yàngzi, dōu shì nǐ! It was all your fault the outing became such a flop. d [pronounced with stress; indicating certainty] 他是去了。 Tā shì qù le. He did go. 天气是冷。 Tiānqì shì lěng. It is cold indeed. 他的工作效率是高。 Tā de gōngzuò xiàolǜ shì gāo. He is really efficient. 5 be just right 这场雨下的是时候。 Zhè cháng yǔ xià de shì shíhou. This rain has come at just the right time. 工具放的不是地方。 Gōngjù fàng de bù shì dìfāng. The tools are not put in the right place. 6 [before nouns at the beginning of the sentence, followed by 都 or 就] every; all; any 是公众的事, 大家都要关心。 Shì gōngzhòng de shì, dàjiā dōu yào guānxīn. Whatever concerns the public concerns us all. 是什么样的老师, 就教出什么样的学生。 Shì shénmeyàng de lǎoshī, jiù jiào chū shénmeyàng de xuésheng. Like teacher, like student. 是什么种子, 就开出什么花。 Shì shénme zhǒngzi, jiù kāi chū shénme huā. Each kind of seed produces its own flowers. 7 [between two identical words] a [used together with 就 or 总 to indicate actuality] 事实总是事实, 谁也否认不了的。 Shìshí zǒng shì shìshí, shuí yě fǒurèn bùliǎo de. Facts are facts, and no one can deny them. 不懂就是不懂, 不要装懂。 Bù dǒng jiù shì bù dǒng, bùyào zhuāng dǒng. If you don’t know, you don’t know, don’t pretend. b [in a clause of concession] 工作忙是忙, 可是大家很愉快。 Gōngzuò máng shì máng, kě shì dàjiā hěn yúkuài. We are busy to be sure, but every one is very happy. 诗是好诗, 就是长了点儿。 Shī shì hǎo shī, jiùshì cháng le diǎnr. It is a good poem all right, but it’s a bit too long. 这东西旧是旧, 但还可以用。 Zhè dōngxi jiù shì jiù, dàn hái kěyǐ yòng. Yes, it’s old, but it can still be used. c [in two parallel clauses to indicate mutual exclusiveness] 他是他, 我是我, 我们毫不相干。 Tā shì tā,  wǒ shì wǒ, wǒmen háobùxiānggān. He is he, I am I; we have nothing to do with each other. d [in two or three parallel clauses to indicate thoroughness or excellence of performance] 他演得真好, 表情是表情, 身段是身段, 做功是做功。 Tā yǎn de zhēn hǎo,  biǎoqíng shì biǎoqíng,  shēnduàn shì shēnduàn, zuògōng shì zuò gōng. He is a marvellous actor; his expressions, movements, and gestures are the best. 8 [in yes-no questions] 你是不是明天去游泳？ (= 你是明天去游泳不是？) Nǐ shì bù shì míngtiān qù yóuyǒng？ (or) nǐ shì míngtiān qù yóuyǒng bù shì？ Are you going swimming tomorrow? 9 [in alternative questions] 你坐火车呢, 还是坐汽车？ Nǐ zuò huǒchē ne, hái shì zuò qìchē? Are you going by train or by bus? 这件事是真是假, 谁也搞不清。 Zhè jiàn shì shì zhēn shì jiǎ, shuí yě gǎo bù qīng. Nobody knows whether it’s true or not. 
verb 1 [in affirmative answers] yes; right 是, 我就去。 Shì, wǒ jiù qù. Yes, I’ll go right away. 是, 我们一定完成任务。 Shì, wǒmen yīdìng wánchéng rènwu. Right, we will complete the task. 2 literary praise; justify See 30253568是古非今shi4gu3fei1jin1是古非今 
adjective correct; right 你说得是。 Nǐ shuō de shì. What you said is right. or You are quite right. 应当早做准备才是。 Yīngdāng zǎo zuò zhǔnbèi cái shì. Preparing early is the right thing to do. or It’s right to prepare early. 
noun right (opp. 非) See 30252288是非shi4fei1是非 
pronoun literary this; that 如是 rúshì like this 由是可知 Yóu shì kězhī from this you can see 是日天气晴朗。 Shì rì tiānqì qínglǎng. It was fine that day. or It was a fine day.</defn>
            </entry>
            <dictref dictid="PACE" entryid="30251008"/>
            <catassign category="HSK 2012-2018/Level 1"/>
            <catassign category="100/Freq10"/>
            <catassign category="LP1"/>
        </card>
        <card language="chinese">
            <entry>
                <headword charset="sc">说</headword>
                <headword charset="tc">說</headword>
                <pron type="hypy" tones="numbers">shuo1</pron>
                <defn>verb 1 speak; talk; say 说风凉话 shuōfēngliánghuà make irresponsible and carping comments 说得多做得少 Shuō de duō zuò de shǎo talk much but do little 说的比唱的好听 shuō de bǐ chàng de hǎo tīng mouth high-sounding words 说得好不如做得好。 shuō de hǎo bùrú zuòdé hǎo. Better to do well than to say well. 他说法语。 Tā shuō Fǎyǔ. He speaks French. 你说得很对。 Nǐ shuō de hěn duì. What you say is quite true. 那未免说得太轻了。 Nà wèimiǎn shuō de tài qīng le. That’s putting it too mildly. 2 explain 说不通 shuōbùtōng cannot hold water; do not make sense 我一说他就明白了。 Wǒ yī shuō tā jiù míngbai le. I told him how and he caught on at once. 他说了又说, 我还是不懂。 Tā shuō le yòu shuō, wǒ háishi bù dǒng. He explained and explained, but I still couldn’t understand. 3 scold 他父亲说了他一顿。 Tā fùqin shuō le tā yī dùn. His father gave him a scolding (or talking-to). 4 act as matchmaker 给他说个媳妇儿 Gěi tā shuō ge xífùr find a wife for him 5 refer to; indicate 你的话是说谁呢？ Nǐ de huà shì shuō shuí ne？ Who did your remarks refer to? 
noun theory; teachings; doctrine 著书立说 zhùshūlìshuō write books to expound a theory</defn>
            </entry>
            <dictref dictid="PACE" entryid="30714112"/>
            <catassign category="HSK 2012-2018/Level 1"/>
            <catassign category="100/Freq40"/>
        </card>
        <card language="chinese">
            <entry>
                <headword charset="sc">他</headword>
                <headword charset="tc">他</headword>
                <pron type="hypy" tones="numbers">ta1</pron>
                <defn>pronoun 1 he; him; his 他哥 tā gē his elder brother 他俩 tāliǎ the two of them; both 他老婆 tā lǎopo his wife 他家在农村。 Tā jiā zài nóngcūn. His home is in the countryside. 他家是新搬来的。 Tā jiā shì xīn bān lái de. He and his family moved here recently. 他刚才给你送票来了。 Tā gāng cái gěi nǐ sòng piào lái le. He came just now with a ticket for you. 谁没有票, 问他要。 Shuí méi yǒu piào, wèn tā yào. Anyone without a ticket can ask him for one. 2 [for either sex when it is either unknown or unimportant] 从远处看不出他是男是女。 cóng yuǎnchù kànbuchū tā shì nán shì nǚ. I can’t tell if it’s a man or a woman from a distance. 每个孩子都讲了他学习(雷锋)的收获。 Měi ge háizi dōu jiǎng le tā xuéxí Léi Fēng de shōuhuò. Each child described what he or she had learnt (from Lei Feng). 3 [before or after a person&apos;s name for emphasis] 老王他也提前到了。 Lǎo wáng tā yě tíqián dào le. Lao Wang also came early. 这事儿成与不成就看他老张了。 Zhè shìr chéng yǔ bù chéng jiù kàn tā lǎo zhāng le. The success or failure of this all depends on Lao Zhang alone. 4 [used as a meaningless object, for emphasis or in fun] 好好睡他一觉 Hǎohāo shuì tā yī jiào have a good sleep 咱们喝他几杯去。 Zánmen hē tā jǐ bēi qù. Let’s go and have a few drinks. 你写他两三本书, 就出名了。 Nǐ xiě tā liǎng sān běn shū, jiù chūmíng le. If you can publish a couple of books, you’ll become famous. 5 usually literary other; another; some other 别无他求 Bié wú tā qiú have no other request 留作他用 liú zuò tāyòng keep for other uses 此人早已他去。 Cǐ rén zǎoyǐ tā qù. He has long since left. 
noun (Tā) a surname</defn>
            </entry>
            <dictref dictid="PACE" entryid="31038720"/>
            <catassign category="HSK 2012-2018/Level 1"/>
            <catassign category="100/Freq10"/>
        </card>
        <card language="chinese">
            <entry>
                <headword charset="sc">她</headword>
                <headword charset="tc">她</headword>
                <pron type="hypy" tones="numbers">ta1</pron>
                <defn>pronoun she; her 她好久没来这儿了。 Tā hǎojiǔ méi lái zhèr le. She hasn’t been here for a long time. 我明天找她去。 Wǒ míngtiān zhǎo tā qù. I’m going to see her tomorrow.</defn>
            </entry>
            <dictref dictid="PACE" entryid="31042048"/>
            <catassign category="HSK 2012-2018/Level 1"/>
            <catassign category="100/Freq100"/>
        </card>
        <card language="chinese">
            <entry>
                <headword charset="sc">我</headword>
                <headword charset="tc">我</headword>
                <pron type="hypy" tones="numbers">wo3</pron>
                <defn>pronoun 1 I; me 2 we; us 敌退我追。 dí tuì wǒ zhuī. We pursue the enemy if they retreat. 3 my; our 我方 wǒfāng our side; we 我国 wǒguó our country 我家 wǒjiā my family; my home 我军 wǒjūn our army 4 [with 你 in parallel structures] one; anyone 大家你帮我, 我帮你, 很快就把活儿干完了。 Dàjiā nǐ bāng wǒ,  wǒ bāng nǐ, hěn kuài jiù bǎ huór gàn wán le. Everyone pitched in and the job was soon done. 5 self 忘我 wàngwǒ oblivious of oneself 自我 zìwǒ self; oneself</defn>
            </entry>
            <dictref dictid="PACE" entryid="32397056"/>
            <catassign category="HSK 2012-2018/Level 1"/>
            <catassign category="100/Freq10"/>
        </card>
        <card language="chinese">
            <entry>
                <headword charset="sc">下</headword>
                <headword charset="tc">下</headword>
                <pron type="hypy" tones="numbers">xia4</pron>
                <defn>noun 1 [used alone, esp. in contrast to 上] below 上有父母, 下有儿女 Shàng yǒu fùmǔ, xià yǒu ér-nǚ have parents above and children below—have a large family to care for 上至市长, 下至一般市民 shàng zhì shìzhǎng, xià zhì yībān shìmín from the mayor down to ordinary townsfolk 2 [after a preposition] down; downward 往下看 wǎng xià kàn look down 他将帽沿向下拉了拉。 Tā jiāng mào yán xiàng xià lā le lā. He pulled his hat down slightly. 3 [after a noun] under 山下 shān xià at the foot of a hill 树下 shù xià under a tree 零下五度 língxià wǔ dù five degrees below zero 在月光下散步 zài yuèguāng xià sànbù take a walk in the moonlight 4 [usu. before a noun] lower (in position, rank, or quality) 分为上, 中, 下三等 fēnwéi shàng, zhōng, xià sānděng divided into three grades: upper, middle and lower 那本书在书架的最下一层。 Nà běn shū zài shūjià de zuì xià yī céng. The book is on the bottom shelf. 5 next (in time or order); latter; second 下次 xiàcì next time 下礼拜 xiàlǐbài next week 下两批 xià liǎng pī next two batches 下个世纪 xià ge shìjì next century 下一班车 xià yī bānchē next bus or train 6 the second of two, or the last of three 下集 xiàjí Volume Two or Three; Vol. II or III 下半学期 Xià bàn xuéqī second (or latter) half of the term 这部词典分上, 中, 下三册。 zhè bù cídiǎn fēn shàng, zhōng, xià sān cè. This dictionary comes in three volumes. 7 [before a verb] downward; down 防止圆木下滑 fángzhǐ yuán mù xiàhuá prevent the logs from rolling down 8 [indicating scope, state, condition, etc.] 在党的领导下 zài dǎng de lǐngdǎo xià under the leadership of the Party 在这种情况下 zài zhèzhǒng qíngkuàng xià under these circumstances 在朋友们的帮助下 Zài péngyou men de bāngzhù xià with the help of friends 9 [in certain expressions of time] 时下 shíxià nowadays 年下 niánxià colloquial the lunar new year 10 [after numerals to indicate location or direction] 四下 sìxià far and near; all around 两下里 liǎngxiàli colloquial both parties; both sides 
verb 1 proceed down from; descend 下床 xiàchuáng get out of bed 下楼 xiàlóu descend the stairs; go or come downstairs 下山 xiàshān descend the mountain; come or go down a mountain 顺流而下 shùnliú&apos;érxià sail or go downstream 2 get off or get out of (a conveyance); alight; disembark 下车 xiàchē get off a car or bus 下电梯 xià diàntī get off an elevator 下飞机 xià fēijī get off a plane; alight from a plane; disembark 3 (of rain, snow, etc.) come down; fall 下雨 xiàyǔ rain 下雪 xiàxuě snow 下雹子了。 Xià báozi le. It’s hailing. 下霜了。 Xià shuāng le. There is frost. 下雾了。 Xià wù le. There’s a fog. 雪下得很大。 Xuě xià de hěn dà. A heavy snow is falling. or It’s snowing hard. 4 issue (an order, etc.); deliver; send out (an invitation, etc.) 下命令 xià mìnglìng issue (or give) orders 下请帖 xià qǐngtiě send an invitation 我们早下过通知了。 Wǒmen zǎo xià guò tōngzhī le. We have already sent out notices. 下订单 xiàdìngdān place an order 5 go to (a place usu. thought of as lower or below) 下地狱 xià dìyù go to hell 下馆子 xià guǎnzi go to eat in a restaurant; eat out 厂长下车间了。 Chǎngzhǎng xià chējiān le. The factory director has gone to the workshop. 6 leave (the stage, field, etc.); exit 这场戏你从右边的旁门下。 Zhè chǎng xì nǐ cóng yòubian de pángmén xià. In this scene, you exit stage right. 换人, 四号下, 三号上。 Huànrén,  sì hào xià, sān hào shàng. Substitution, No. 3 on, No. 4 off. 7 put in (ingredients or components of food, fertilizer, poison, capital, etc.); cast 下肥料 xià féiliào apply fertilizer 下面条 xiàmian tiáo place noodles in a pot of boiling water; cook noodles in boiling water 下作料 Xià zuóliao put in the condiments; add seasonings; season 下网捞鱼 xià wǎng lāo yú cast a net to catch fish 8 play (a board game); make a move (in a board game) 下围棋 xià wéiqí play go 该你下了。 Gāi nǐ xià le. Your move. 9 take down or off; dismantle; unload 下了歹徒的枪 xià le dǎitú de qiāng disarm the brigand 把纱窗下下来 bǎ shāchuāng xià xiàlai take the screen window off 船上的货还没下完。 Chuánshàng de huò hái méi xià wán. The cargo is not fully unloaded yet. 10 give (a definition, conclusion, etc.) 下定义 xià dìngyì give a definition；define 下结论 xià jiélùn draw a conclusion 下决心 xià juéxīn make a resolution;determine;resolve to 11 apply; use 下刀 xià dāo cut; slice; put a knife to 下力气 xià lìqi apply strength; make an effort; exert oneself 12 (of animals) give birth to; drop (a litter); lay (eggs) 下了一窝小猪 xià le yī wō xiǎo zhū give birth to (or drop) a litter of piglets 13 capture (a city); take 连下数城 lián xià shù chéng take several cities in succession 14 give in 相持不下 xiāngchíbùxià deadlock 15 get off (work); get out of (class) 下夜班 xià yèbān come off night duty 课早下了。 Kè zǎo xià le. The class was over a long time ago. 16 [in the negative] less than; at least 参加大会的不下三千人。 Cānjiā dàhuì de bù xià sānqiān rén. No less than 3,000 people attended the conference. or At least 3,000 people came to the conference. 
measure word 1  a [for verbs of action] stroke; time(s) 敲三下门 qiāo sān xià mén give three knocks on the door 推了我一下 Tuī le wǒ yīxià gave me a push 打了孩子几下 dǎ le háizi jǐ xià spanked the child a couple of times 摇了几下旗子 yáo le jǐ xià qízi waved the flag a few times b [for the capacity of a container] dialect 瓶子里装了半下墨水。 Píngzi lǐ zhuāng le bàn xià mòshuǐ. The bottle is half full of ink. 这么大碗面条, 他足足吃了三下。 Zhème dà wǎn miàntiáo, tā zúzú chī le sān xià. He wolfed down three large bowls of noodles. 2 [after 两 or 几] skill; ability; capability 我就会这么两下。 Wǒ jiù huì zhème liǎng xià. That’s all I can do. 想不到他还有几下。 Xiǎng bù dào tā háiyǒu jǐ xià. I never expected him to be so capable.</defn>
            </entry>
            <dictref dictid="PACE" entryid="32799232"/>
            <catassign category="HSK 2012-2018/Level 1"/>
            <catassign category="100/Freq50"/>
        </card>
        <card language="chinese">
            <entry>
                <headword charset="sc">想</headword>
                <headword charset="tc">想</headword>
                <pron type="hypy" tones="numbers">xiang3</pron>
                <defn>verb 1 think; ponder; consider 想办法 xiǎng bànfǎ think of a way; seek a solution (or a way out) 想问题 xiǎng wèntí think over a problem 让我想一想。 Ràng wǒ xiǎng yī xiǎng. Let me think it over. or Let me see. 你想得真周到。 Nǐ xiǎng de zhēn zhōudao. You have really thought of everything. 你想清楚了没有？ Nǐ xiǎng qīngchu le méiyǒu？ Have you thought it out (or through)? 我们也要想想困难。 Wǒmen yě yào xiǎngxiǎng kùnnan. We must also anticipate difficulties. 我在想下一步棋该怎么走。 Wǒ zài xiǎng xià yī bù qí gāi zěnme zǒu. I’m considering my next (chess) move. 2 think back; try to remember; recall; recollect 回想往事 huí xiǎng wǎngshì recall the past 你好好想想钥匙搁哪儿了。 Nǐ hǎohāo xiǎngxiǎng yàoshi gē nǎr le. Think back carefully where you could have put the key. 3 suppose; reckon; consider; think 我想不至于吧。 Wǒ xiǎng bùzhìyú ba. I don’t believe things could get that bad. or Surely as bad as that! 我想我该走了。 Wǒ xiǎng wǒ gāi zǒu le. I’m afraid I must be going now. 你想他能买到票吗？ Nǐ xiǎng tā néng mǎi dào piào ma？ Do you suppose he can get the tickets? 我想他今天不会来。 Wǒ xiǎng tā jīntiān bù huì lái. I don’t think he’ll come today. 4 want to; wish to; feel like (doing sth.) 我也想试试。 Wǒ yě xiǎng shìshi. I’d like to try too. 他很想上大学。 Tā hěn xiǎng shàng dàxué. He longs to go to college. 你想看足球赛吗？ Nǐ xiǎng kàn zúqiúsài ma？ Do you want to see (or feel like seeing) a football match? 她不想跟我们去。 Tā bù xiǎng gēn wǒmen qù. She doesn’t wish to come with us. 5 remember with longing; miss 你走了以后, 我们都很想你。 Nǐ zǒu le yǐhòu, wǒmen dōu hěn xiǎng nǐ. After you left, we all missed you. 王大娘想女儿都想病了。 Wáng dàniáng xiǎng nǚ&apos;ér dōu xiǎng bìng le. Auntie Wang misses her daughter so much she’s fallen ill.</defn>
            </entry>
            <dictref dictid="PACE" entryid="33072896"/>
            <catassign category="HSK 2012-2018/Level 1"/>
            <catassign category="100/Freq100"/>
            <catassign category="LP1"/>
        </card>
        <card language="chinese">
            <entry>
                <headword charset="sc">小</headword>
                <headword charset="tc">小</headword>
                <pron type="hypy" tones="numbers">xiao3</pron>
                <defn>noun 1 little ones; children 一家大小 yī jiā dà xiǎo the whole family, old and young 上有老下有小 shàngyǒulǎoxiàyǒuxiǎo have the old above and the young below—have parents and children to care for 2 dated concubine 讨个小 tǎo ge xiǎo take a concubine 
adjective 1 small; little; petty; minor (opp. 大) 小国 xiǎoguó small country 小河 xiǎohé small river 小事 xiǎoshì small matter 小屋 xiǎowū small room (or house) 小姑娘 xiǎogūniang little girl 小手术 xiǎoshǒushù minor operation 小问题 xiǎo wèntí minor question 风小些了。 Fēng xiǎo xiē le. The wind has dropped a little. 那个数量很小。 Nàge shùliàng hěn xiǎo. That’s a very small amount. 你的声音太小。 Nǐ de shēngyīn tài xiǎo. Your voice is too soft. 鞋小了点儿。 xié xiǎo le diǎnr. These shoes are a bit too tight. 2 young (opp. 大, 老) 你也不小了。 Nǐ yě bù xiǎo le. You’re not young any more. 她比我小。 Tā bǐ wǒ xiǎo. She is younger than I am. 他还小呢。 Tā hái xiǎo ne. He’s still young. 3 the last in order of seniority; youngest 小儿子 xiǎo&apos;érzi the youngest son 他是我的小弟弟。 Tā shì wǒ dexiǎo dìdi. He is my youngest brother. 4 [before names of animals to indicate the young] 小狗 xiǎo gǒu pup; puppy 小鸡 xiǎojī chick 小鹿 xiǎolù deerlet; fawn 小马 xiǎomǎ pony; foal; colt 小猫 xiǎomāo kitten; kitty 小牛 xiǎoniú calf; heifer 小鸭 xiǎoyā duckling 小羊 xiǎoyáng lamb; kid 小猪 xiǎozhū piggy; piglet; shoat 小老虎 xiǎolǎohǔ tiger cub 5 [before family name, given name, etc.] 小强 xiǎo qiáng Xiao Qiang 小三儿 xiǎo sānr Xiao Sanr (childhood name for one’s third child) 小张 xiǎo zhāng Xiao Zhang 6 self-deprecating my; our 小店 xiǎodiàn my store 小女 xiǎonǚ my daughter 
adverb of short duration; for a while 小坐片刻 xiǎozuòpiànkè sit for a while</defn>
            </entry>
            <dictref dictid="PACE" entryid="33158656"/>
            <catassign category="HSK 2012-2018/Level 1"/>
            <catassign category="100/Freq90"/>
        </card>
        <card language="chinese">
            <entry>
                <headword charset="sc">些</headword>
                <headword charset="tc">些</headword>
                <pron type="hypy" tones="numbers">xie1</pron>
                <defn>measure word some; a few 买些东西 mǎi xiē dōngxi do some shopping 前些日子 qiánxiē rìzi a few days ago; sometime ago 作了些改进 Zuò le xiē gǎijìn have made some improvements 
adverb [after adjectives] a little more; a little 留神些！ Liúshén xiē! Be careful! 请大声些！ Qǐng dàshēng xiē! Louder, please! 他的烧退了些。 Tā de shāo tuì le xiē. His fever has come down a little. 我好些了。 Wǒ hǎo xiē le. I’m a little better. 这个稍大些。 Zhège shāo dà xiē. This is a little bigger.</defn>
            </entry>
            <dictref dictid="PACE" entryid="33263104"/>
            <catassign category="HSK 2012-2018/Level 1"/>
            <catassign category="100/Freq90"/>
        </card>
        <card language="chinese">
            <entry>
                <headword charset="sc">一</headword>
                <headword charset="tc">一</headword>
                <pron type="hypy" tones="numbers">yi1</pron>
                <defn>number 1 one 一万一 yīwàn yī eleven thousand 一匹马 yī pǐ mǎ a horse 一瓶牛奶 yī píng niúnǎi one bottle of milk 2 first 一级 yījí of first rate 一路车 yī lù chē No. 1 bus 一营一连 yī yíng yīlián First Company of the First Battalion 3 single; alone; only one 一枪就打中了目标 yī qiāng jiù dǎ zhōng le mùbiāo hit the target with a single shot 你一个人行吗？ Nǐ yī ge rén xíng ma？ Can you manage all by yourself? 4 same 一根藤上的苦瓜 Yī gēn téng shàng de kǔguā bitter gourds from the same vine—people with a similar bitter past 意见不一。 Yìjian bùyī. Opinions differ. 这不是一码事。 Zhè bù shì yī mǎ shì. This is another pair of shoes. 这姑娘跟她妈妈一个模样。 Zhè gūniang gēn tā māma yī ge múyàng. The girl is the image of her mother. 5 whole; all; throughout 一冬 Yīdōng the whole winter; all winter; throughout the winter 他一脸的土。 Tā yī liǎn de tǔ. His face was covered with dust. 一包在内花了二百块钱。 yī bāo zàinèi huāle èrbǎi kuài qián. I spent 200 yuan, fares, hotel, meals all included. 一屋子的人都欢腾起来。 Yī wūzi de rén dōu huānténg qǐlai. Everybody in the house was overjoyed. 6 every time 大家一提起那艰苦创业的日子, 总有说不完的话。 Dàjiā yī tíqǐ nà jiānkǔ chuàngyè de rìzi, zǒng yǒu shuō bù wán de huà. Every time we talk about the hard pioneering days, we have so much to say that we can’t get it all out. 7 also; otherwise 汞溴红一名红汞。 Gǒngxiùhóng yī míng hónggǒng. Merbromin is also known as mercurochrome. 8 concentrated; wholehearted 专心一意 zhuānxīnyīyì single-minded; concentrated 9 [indicating that the action occurs just once or lasts for a short time] a [in the middle of a reduplicated verb] 等一等 děng yī děng wait a bit 歇一歇 xiēyīxiē have a rest 笑一笑 xiàoyīxiào give a smile b [between a verb and a verbal measure] 咳一声 hāi yī shēng give a cough 瞧一眼 Qiáo yī yǎn take a look 咬一口 yǎo yī kǒu take a bite 打他一巴掌 dǎ tā yī bāzhang give him a slap 10 [before a verb or a verbal measure to indicate an action to be followed by a result] 一查到底 yī chá dàodǐ investigate fully 一跳跳了过去 yī tiào tiào le guòqu get over in one jump 经他这么一说, 大家又都有信心了。 Jīng tā zhème yī shuō, dàjiā yòu dōu yǒu xìnxīn le. His words restored our confidence. 医生一检查, 果然是肺炎。 Yīshēng yī jiǎnchá, guǒrán shì fèiyán. The doctor’s check-up confirmed that it was pneumonia. 11 [before a verb or an adjective, indicating the suddenness or thoroughness of an action or a change in the situation] 那马猛然一惊, 直立起来。 Nà mǎ měngrán yī jīng, zhí lì qǐlai. All of a sudden the horse shied and reared in fright. 这部电影值得一看。 Zhè bù diànyǐng zhíde yī kàn. This movie is well worth seeing. 
adverb once; as soon as 他一回来我就告诉他。 Tā yī huílai wǒ jiù gàosu tā. I will tell him as soon as he comes back. 
preposition per; a 一班十个人 yī bān shí gèrén ten in a class 一小时六十公里 yī xiǎoshí liùshí gōnglǐ (at) 60 kilometres per hour 
auxiliary literary [before certain words for emphasis] 事态之严重一至于此！ Shìtài zhī yánzhòng yī zhì yú cǐ! To think that things should have come to such a pass! 吏呼一何怒, 妇啼一何苦。(杜甫《石壕吏》) lì hū yī hé nù, fù tí yī hékǔ. The officer’s shouting, how angry it was; | The woman’s cry, how mournful and bitter! 
noun music note of the scale in gongchepu (工尺谱), corresponding to 7 in numbered musical notation</defn>
            </entry>
            <dictref dictid="PACE" entryid="34332672"/>
            <catassign category="HSK 2012-2018/Level 1"/>
            <catassign category="100/Freq10"/>
        </card>
        <card language="chinese">
            <entry>
                <headword charset="sc">在</headword>
                <headword charset="tc">在</headword>
                <pron type="hypy" tones="numbers">zai4</pron>
                <defn>verb 1 exist; be alive 人在人情在。 Rén zài rénqíng zài. Friendship lasts as long as the person remains. 他父亲还在, 母亲早就不在了。 Tā fùqin hái zài, mǔqin zǎo jiù bù zài le. His father is still alive, but his mother passed away long ago. 她人已去, 但精神永在。 tā rén yǐqù, dàn jīngshén yǒng zài. She is gone, but her spirit lives on. 问题还在, 并没有解决。 Wèntí hái zài, bìng méiyǒu jiějué. The problem still exists and is not resolved yet. 2 be at, in, or on (a place) 你去那儿找他, 他准在。 Nǐ qù nàr zhǎo tā, tā zhǔn zài. Go and see him; he’s sure to be there. 他在家, 不在这儿。 Tā zài jiā, bù zài zhèr. He’s at home, not here. 你的钢笔在桌子上呢。 Nǐ de gāngbǐ zài zhuōzi shàng ne. Your pen is on the table. 我父母在农村。 Wǒ fùmǔ zài nóngcūn. My parents are in the countryside. 3 depend on; rest with 去不去在你自己。 Qù bù qù zài nǐ zìjǐ. It’s up to you whether to go or not. 收不收他在学校领导。 Shōu bù shōu tā zài xuéxiào lǐngdǎo. His admittance rests with the school authorities. 学习好, 主要在自己努力。 Xuéxí hǎo, zhǔyào zài zìjǐ nǔlì. Getting good results in one’s studies depends mainly on one’s own efforts. 4 lie in; consist in 工作人员不在多, 而在有效率。 Gōngzuò rényuán bù zài duō, ér zài yǒu xiàolǜ. A staff need not be large but it must be efficient. 她美就美在那双眼睛。 Tā měi jiù měi zài nà shuāng yǎnjing. Her charm lies in her eyes. 我们的希望在青年一代。 Wǒmen de xīwàng zài qīngnián yīdài. Our hopes lie in the younger generation. 学习贵在坚持。 Xuéxí guì zài jiānchí. Persistence is vital to study. 这首诗妙在含蓄而不明言。 Zhè shǒu shī miào zài hánxù ér bù míng yán. The appeal of this poem lies in inference rather than direct statement. 5 join or belong to an organization; be a member of an organization 在组织 Zài zǔzhī belong to a certain organization 6 be on the job or at the post See 35602688在职zai4zhi2在职 
preposition 1 at, in, or on (a place or time) 在会上发言 Zài huì shàng fāyán speak at a meeting 狗在地上打滚儿。 Gǒu zài dìshang dǎgǔnr. The dog rolled on the ground. 他在工厂工作。 Tā zài gōngchǎng gōngzuò. He works in a factory. 事情发生在去年。 Shìqing fāshēng zài qùnián. It happened last year. 阳光照射在水面上。 Yángguāng zhàoshè zài shuǐmiàn shàng. The sunlight fell on the water. 运动会安排在四月份。 Yùndònghuì ānpái zài Sìyuè fèn. The sports meet will be some time in April. 2 according to; in terms of 在党内 zài dǎngnèi within (or inside) the Party 在此期间 zài cǐ qījiān during this period 在理论上 zài lǐlùn shàng in theory; theoretically 在我看来 Zài wǒ kànlai in my opinion; as I see it 在这方面 zài zhè fāngmiàn in this respect 在国际事务中 zài guójì shìwù zhōng in international affairs 在全国范围内 zài quánguó fànwéi nèi throughout the country 在这种情况下 zài zhèzhǒng qíngkuàng xià under these circumstances 在党中央的领导下 zài dǎngzhōngyāng de lǐngdǎo xià under the leadership of the Party Central Committee 在和平共处五项原则的基础上 zài hépíng gòngchǔ wǔ xiàng yuánzé de jīchǔ shàng on the basis of the Five Principles of Peaceful Coexistence 
adverb 1 [indicating action in progress] 他在看电视。 Tā zài kàn diànshì. He’s watching TV. 他在干什么？——他还在睡觉呢。 Tā zài gàn shénme？ —— tā hái zài shuìjiào ne. What’s he doing? —He’s still sleeping. 她在游泳。 Tā zài yóuyǒng. She is swimming. 2 [used together with 所 (suǒ) and often followed by 不 (bù) to indicate emphasis] See 35597056在所不辞zai4suo3bu4ci2在所不辞;35597312在所不惜zai4suo3bu4xi1 在所不惜</defn>
            </entry>
            <dictref dictid="PACE" entryid="35592192"/>
            <catassign category="HSK 2012-2018/Level 1"/>
            <catassign category="100/Freq10"/>
        </card>
        <card language="chinese">
            <entry>
                <headword charset="sc">这</headword>
                <headword charset="tc">這</headword>
                <pron type="hypy" tones="numbers">zhe4</pron>
                <defn>pronoun 1 this 这地方 zhè dìfang this place 这一回 zhè yī huí this time 这就对了。 Zhè jiù duì le. Now you’re on the right track. or Now that’s better. 这是新产品。 zhè shì xīnchǎnpǐn. These are new products. 这究竟是怎么回事？ Zhè jiūjìng shì zěnme huí shì？ What’s all this about? 这才是好孩子！ Zhè cái shì hǎo háizi! That’s a good boy (girl)! or That’s a dear! 这消息我知道了。 Zhè xiāoxi wǒ zhīdao le. I’ve heard that news already. or Yes, so I’ve heard. 2 now 我这就走。 Wǒ zhè jiù zǒu. I’m leaving right now. 他这才知道锻炼身体的好处。 Tā zhè cái zhīdao duànliàn shēntǐ de hǎochu. Only now does he see the benefit of exercise.</defn>
            </entry>
            <dictref dictid="PACE" entryid="35937792"/>
            <catassign category="HSK 2012-2018/Level 1"/>
            <catassign category="100/Freq20"/>
        </card>
        <card language="chinese">
            <entry>
                <headword charset="sc">从</headword>
                <headword charset="tc">從</headword>
                <pron type="hypy" tones="numbers">cong2</pron>
                <defn>verb 1 follow; comply with; obey 从大流 cóng dà liú follow the general public 2 join; be engaged in See 19188736从军cong2jun1从军 3 follow the principle of; employ the method of 训练要从严从难。 Xùnliàn yào cóngyán cóng nán. Training should be hard and strict. 
noun dated 1 follower; attendant 从人 cóngrén followers; retinue 2 relationship between cousins, etc. of the same paternal grandfather or great-grandfather 从兄弟 cóng xiōng-dì cousins on the paternal side; cousins 
adjective secondary; accessary 主从关系 zhǔcóng guānxi principal and subordinate relations 
preposition 1 from (a time, a place, or a point of view) 从零开始 cóng líng kāishǐ start from scratch (or nothing) 从现在起 cóng xiànzài qǐ from now on 从根本上说 cóng gēnběn shàng shuō essentially; in essence 从全局出发 cóng quánjú chūfā proceed from the situation as a whole 从这儿往西 cóng zhèr wǎng xī go west from here; west of here 从我做起, 从现在做起。 cóng wǒ zuòqǐ, cóng xiànzài zuòqǐ. Begin from myself, and begin right now. 2 via, through, or past (a place) 从门缝里往外看 cóng ménfèng lǐ wǎng wài kàn peep outside through a crevice in the door 从学校门前经过 Cóng xuéxiào mén qián jīngguò pass the school gate 你从桥上过, 我从桥下走。 Nǐ cóng qiáo shàng guò, wǒ cóng qiáo xià zǒu. You go over the bridge, I’ll go under it. 
adverb [followed by a negative] ever 从不计较个人的名誉地位 Cóngbù jìjiào gèrén de míngyù dìwèi never give any consideration to personal fame or position 从没听说过。 Cóng méi tīngshuō guò. Never heard of it. 她在成绩面前从不骄傲。 Tā zài chéngjì miànqián cóngbù jiāo&apos;ào. Her head was never turned by success.</defn>
            </entry>
            <dictref dictid="PACE" entryid="19185152"/>
            <catassign category="HSK 2012-2018/Level 2"/>
            <catassign category="100/Freq100"/>
        </card>
        <card language="chinese">
            <entry>
                <headword charset="sc">到</headword>
                <headword charset="tc">到</headword>
                <pron type="hypy" tones="numbers">dao4</pron>
                <defn>verb 1 arrive; reach 到！ Dào! [answer to roll call] Here! 到了多少人？ Dào le duōshao rén？ How many people were present? 火车到站了。 Huǒchē dào zhàn le. The train has arrived at the station. 时间到了。 Shíjiān dào le. Time’s up. 2 go to; leave for 到兰州去 Dào Lánzhōu qù go to Lanzhou 3 [as a verb complement to show the result of an action] 办得到 bàndedào can be done 说到做到 shuōdàozuòdào be as good as one’s word 想不到你来了。 Xiǎng bù dào nǐ lái le. I didn’t expect you would come. 
preposition up until; up to 到目前为止 dào mùqián wéizhǐ up to the present; until now; so far 工作到深夜 Gōngzuò dào shēnyè work late into the night 从星期三到星期五 cóng Xīngqīsān dào Xīngqīwǔ from Wednesday to Friday 温度降到零下二十度。 Wēndù jiàng dào língxià èrshí dù. The temperature dropped to minus 20 degrees centigrade. 
adjective thoughtful; considerate 不到之处请原谅。 Bù dào zhī chù qǐng yuánliàng. Please excuse me if I have been inconsiderate in any way.</defn>
            </entry>
            <dictref dictid="PACE" entryid="19719424"/>
            <catassign category="HSK 2012-2018/Level 2"/>
            <catassign category="100/Freq40"/>
        </card>
        <card language="chinese">
            <entry>
                <headword charset="sc">得</headword>
                <headword charset="tc">得</headword>
                <pron type="hypy" tones="numbers">de5</pron>
                <defn>auxiliary 1 [after a verb or an adjective to express possibility or capability] 吃不得 chībude inedible 那事做不得！ Nà shì zuò bù de! You mustn’t do that! 这双鞋穿得。 Zhè shuāng xié chuān de. These shoes fit well. 这个人批评不得。 Zhège rén pīpíng bude. He’s not a man to criticize. 咱们可粗心不得。 Zánmen kě cūxīn bude. We can’t afford to be careless. 2 [between a verb and its complement to express possibility] 那办得到。 Nà bàn de dào. That can be done. 我拿得动。 Wǒ ná de dòng. I can carry it. 他做得好做不好？ Tā zuò de hǎo zuò bù hǎo？ Can he do it well? 3 [linking a verb or an adjective to a complement which describes the manner or degree] 唱得不好 chàng de bù hǎo not sing well 写得很好 xiě de hěn hǎo very well written 冷得打哆嗦 lěng de dǎ duōsuo shiver with cold 笑得肚子痛 xiào de dùzi tòng laugh till one’s sides split 他做菜好得很。 tā zuòcài hǎo de hěn. He cooks very well. 他开车小心得很。 Tā kāichē xiǎoxīn de hěn. He drives very carefully.</defn>
            </entry>
            <dictref dictid="PACE" entryid="19780096"/>
            <catassign category="HSK 2012-2018/Level 2"/>
            <catassign category="100/Freq40"/>
        </card>
        <card language="chinese">
            <entry>
                <headword charset="sc">对</headword>
                <headword charset="tc">對</headword>
                <pron type="hypy" tones="numbers">dui4</pron>
                <defn>noun antithetical couplet; couplet 喜对 xǐ duì wedding couplet 
verb 1 answer; reply 无言以对 wúyányǐduì have nothing to say in reply 2 treat; cope with; counter 刀对刀, 枪对枪 dāo duì dāo, qiāng duì qiāng sword against sword and spear against spear 上海队对北京队 Shànghǎi duì duì Běijīng duì Shanghai versus Beijing 3 train on; direct at 枪口对着某人 qiāngkǒu duì zhe mǒurén train the gun on sb. 她的话不是对着你的。 Tā de huà bù shì duì zhe nǐ de. What she said was not directed at you. 4 bring (two things) into contact; fit together 这个榫头对不上。 Zhège sǔntou duì bù shàng. This tenon does not fit. 5 suit; agree; get along 对心眼儿 duìxīnyǎnr suit one very well; compatible 6 compare; check; identify; verify 对笔迹 duì bǐjì identify the handwriting 对号码 duì hàomǎ verify numbers 7 set; adjust 对好望远镜的距离 duì hǎo wàngyuǎnjìng de jùlí adjust the focus of a telescope 8 mix; add 茶太浓了, 给我对点儿水。 Chá tài nóng le, gěi wǒ duì diǎnr shuǐ. Add some water to the tea, it’s too strong for me. 9 divide into halves 对股劈 duìgǔ pī go halves; split fifty-fifty 
adjective 1 opposite; opposing See 59556067对岸dui4an4对岸 2 right; correct 猜对了 cāi duìle guess right 对,  就这么办。 Duì, jiù zhème bàn. All right, just do it. or Yes, that’s what we’ll do. 你说得很对。 Nǐ shuō de hěn duì. What you say is quite true. or You are quite right. 这事你做得对。 Zhè shì nǐ zuò de duì. You did the right thing. 他今天神色不对。 Tā jīntiān shénsè bùduì. He doesn’t look himself today. 
adverb mutual; face to face 对骂 duìmà call each other names; curse each other 对饮 duìyǐn (two people) drink together 对坐 duìzuò sit facing each other 
preposition with regard to; concerning 对健康不利 duì jiànkāng bùlì bad for one’s health; unhealthy 对青少年的教育工作 duì qīng-shàonián de jiàoyù gōngzuò educating young people; education of the young 对这个问题的不同意见 duì zhège wèntí de bùtóng yìjian different views on this question 对犯罪分子实行法律制裁 duì fànzuì fènzǐ shíxíng fǎlǜ zhìcái impose legal sanctions on criminals; punish criminals according to the law 他对父亲很尊敬。 Tā duì fùqin hěn zūnjìng. He has great respect for his father. 这录音机对我来说是够好的了。 Zhè lùyīnjī duì wǒ láishuō shì gòu hǎo de le. This recorder is good enough for me. 
measure word pair; couple 一对夫妇 yī duì fūfù a married couple 一对花瓶 yī duì huāpíng a pair of vases</defn>
            </entry>
            <dictref dictid="PACE" entryid="20381184"/>
            <catassign category="HSK 2012-2018/Level 2"/>
            <catassign category="100/Freq40"/>
        </card>
        <card language="chinese">
            <entry>
                <headword charset="sc">过</headword>
                <headword charset="tc">過</headword>
                <pron type="hypy" tones="numbers">guo5</pron>
                <defn>auxiliary 1 [after a verb to indicate the completion of an action] 桃花都已经开过了。 Táohuā dōu yǐjing kāi guo le. The peach blossoms are over. 我吃过午饭就去。 Wǒ chī guo wǔfàn jiù qù. I’ll go right after lunch. 2 [after a verb or an adjective to indicate a past action or state] 你去过桂林吗？ nǐ qù guo Guìlín ma? Have you ever been to Guilin? 他年轻的时候胖过。 Tā niánqīng de shíhou pàng guo. He used to be fat in his youth.</defn>
            </entry>
            <dictref dictid="PACE" entryid="22210304"/>
            <catassign category="HSK 2012-2018/Level 2"/>
            <catassign category="HSK 2012-2018/Level 3"/>
            <catassign category="100/Freq50"/>
        </card>
        <card language="chinese">
            <entry>
                <headword charset="sc">进</headword>
                <headword charset="tc">進</headword>
                <pron type="hypy" tones="numbers">jin4</pron>
                <defn>verb 1 advance; move forward; move ahead (opp. 退) 向前进 Xiàng qiánjìn move forward 2 enter; come (or go) into; get into (opp. 出) 进屋 jìn wū enter a house or room 进大学 jìn dàxué enter college 进医院 jìn yīyuàn go to hospital; be hospitalized 进工厂当学徒 jìn gōngchǎng dāng xuétú start work in a factory as an apprentice 请进！ Qǐngjìn! Come in! 3 receive; admit 我们单位新进了一个编辑。 Wǒmen dānwèi xīn jìn le yī ge biānjí. Our unit has taken on a new editor. 4 eat; drink; take 进餐 jìncān have a meal 5 submit; present 进一言 Jìn yīyán give a word of advice 6 [as aux., after a verb] into; in 住进新楼 zhù jìn xīn lóu move into a new building 走进商店 Zǒu jìn shāngdiàn walk into the shop 把子弹压进弹匣 bàzi tányā jìn dànxiá press the cartridges into the magazine 7 sports score a goal 进了！ Jìn le! It’s in! or Goal! 这球没进。 Zhè qiú méi jìn. He’s missed it. 
measure word any of the several rows of houses within an old-style residential compound 这座宅院一共三进。 zhè zuò zháiyuàn yīgòng sān jìn. This residential compound has three rows of houses.</defn>
            </entry>
            <dictref dictid="PACE" entryid="24298240"/>
            <catassign category="HSK 2012-2018/Level 2"/>
            <catassign category="100/Freq90"/>
        </card>
        <card language="chinese">
            <entry>
                <headword charset="sc">就</headword>
                <headword charset="tc">就</headword>
                <pron type="hypy" tones="numbers">jiu4</pron>
                <defn>verb 1 come near; move towards 大家就拢来烤火取暖。 Dàjiā jiù lǒng lái kǎohuǒ qǔnuǎn. They all gathered round the fire to get warm. 你就着桌子吃西瓜。 Nǐ jiù zhe zhuōzi chī xīguā. Eat your watermelon over the table. 我们就着路灯下棋。 Wǒmen jiù zhe lùdēng xiàqí. We played chess by the light of a street lamp. 2 undertake; engage in; enter upon 就农 jiù nóng engage in farming 3 accomplish; make 这个鼎是青铜铸就的。 Zhège dǐng shì qīngtóng zhùjiù de. This tripod is made of bronze. 4 take advantage of; accomodate oneself to 我们就这个机会谈谈。 Wǒmen jiù zhège jīhuì tán tán. We’ll take this opportunity to have a talk. 只好就这块料子做了。 Zhǐhǎo jiù zhè kuài liàozi zuò le. We’ll have to make do with this little piece of fabric. 我反正有空, 就你的时间吧。 Wǒ fǎnzheng yǒu kòng, jiù nǐ de shíjiān ba. Make it anytime that suits you; I’m free anyway. 5 be eaten with; go with 炒鸡蛋就饭 Chǎo jīdàn jiù fàn scramble eggs to go with the rice 他用花生就酒。 Tā yòng huāshēng jiù jiǔ. He nibbles peanuts with his drink. 
preposition 1 with regard to; concerning; on 就我所知 jiùwǒsuǒzhī as far as I know 双方就共同关心的问题进行了会谈。 Shuāngfāng jiù gòngtóng guānxīn de wèntí jìnxíng le huìtán. The two sides held talks on matters of common interest. 2 [used to form a set phrase with a passive meaning] 就捕 jiù bǔ be arrested 
adverb 1 at once; right away 我就来。 Wǒ jiù lái. I’ll come right away. or I’m on my way. 我这就去。 Wǒ zhè jiù qù. I’ll go right away. 一会儿就得。 Yīhuìr jiù děi. It’ll be ready in a minute. 2 as early as; already 我星期一就给你钱。 Wǒ Xīngqīyī jiù gěi nǐ qián. I’ll pay you on Monday. 今天我七点钟就来了。 Jīntiān wǒ qī diǎn zhōng jiù lái le. I was here by 7 o’clock today. 3 as soon as; right after 说干就干 shuōgànjiùgàn act without delay 我吃了饭就出去了。 Wǒ chī le fàn jiù chūqu le. As soon as I finished eating, I went out. 我一见他就生气。 Wǒ yī jiàn tā jiù shēngqì. Whenever I see him, I get angry. 他每天下了课就回家。 Tā měitiān xià le kè jiù huíjiā. He comes home every day right after class. 4 in that case; then 要是你来, 我就高兴了。 Yào shì nǐ lái, wǒ jiù gāoxìng le. If you come, (then) I’ll be very happy. 不经过艰苦奋斗, 就不能胜利。 Bù jīngguò jiānkǔfèndòu, jiù bù néng shènglì. All victories are won through arduous struggle. 5 as much as; as many as 光衬衫他就有二十件。 Guāng chènshān tā jiù yǒu èrshí jiàn. He has as many as 20 shirts. 光回收废品一项, 他们就给公司节约了二十万元。 guāng huíshōu fèipǐn yī xiàng, tāmenjiù gěi gōngsī jiéyuē le èrshí wàn yuán. Just by collecting scrap, they saved all of 200,000 yuan for the company. 6 [between two identical elements to express resignation] 丢了就丢了吧, 以后小心点。 Diū le jiù diū le ba, yǐhòu xiǎoxīn diǎn. If it’s lost, it’s lost. Just be more careful from now on. 7 to begin with; as expected 我就料到他会等我们的。 Wǒ jiù liàodào tā huì děng wǒmen de. I knew he’d be waiting for us. 我本来就不懂法语。 Wǒ běnlái jiù bù dǒng fǎ yǔ. I never said I knew any French in the first place. 8 only; merely; just 就这一本了, 看完请马上还。 Jiù zhè yī běn le, kàn wán qǐng mǎ shàng huán. This is the only copy left. Please return it as soon as you finish reading it. 我就要几张纸。 Wǒ jiùyào jǐ zhāng zhǐ. I just want a few sheets of paper. 我就去过一次上海。 Wǒ jiù qù guò yī cì Shànghǎi. I’ve been to Shanghai only once before. 我们就等你的决定了。 Wǒmen jiù děng nǐ de juédìng le. All we need is your decision. 9 just; simply 我就不信我们妇女干不了这一行。 Wǒ jiù bù xìn wǒmen fùnǚ gànbuliǎo zhè yīháng. I just don’t believe we women can’t do this job. 不知道为什么, 我就不喜欢他。 Bùzhīdào wèishénme, wǒ jiù bù xǐhuan tā. I don’t know why I don’t like him. 10 exactly; precisely 医务室就在这儿。 Yīwùshì jiù zài zhèr. This is where the clinic is. 
conjunction even if 你就生气也没用。 Nǐ jiù shēngqì yě méiyòng. Even getting angry won’t help. 你就不说, 我也会知道的。 Nǐ jiù bù shuō, wǒ yě huì zhīdao de. Even if you don’t tell me, I’ll know anyway.</defn>
            </entry>
            <dictref dictid="PACE" entryid="24554752"/>
            <catassign category="HSK 2012-2018/Level 2"/>
            <catassign category="100/Freq40"/>
        </card>
        <card language="chinese">
            <entry>
                <headword charset="sc">要</headword>
                <headword charset="tc">要</headword>
                <pron type="hypy" tones="numbers">yao4</pron>
                <defn>noun main points; essentials 择要记录 Zéyào jìlù note down the essential points 
adjective important; essential 要法 yào fǎ important method; necessary way 上述规定希严格执行为要。 Shàngshù guīdìng xī yángé zhíxíng wéi yào. It is imperative that the above rules be strictly observed. 
verb 1 want; ask for; wish; desire 谁没有票, 问她要。 Shuí méi yǒu piào, wèn tā yào. Anyone without a ticket can ask her for one. 他要一架手风琴。 Tā yào yī jià shǒufēngqín. He wants an accordion. 我要了两个菜。 Wǒ yào le liǎng ge cài. I ordered two dishes. 这双鞋我还要呢。 Zhè shuāng xié wǒ háiyào ne. I want to keep these shoes. 2 ask (or want) sb. to do sth. 不是你要我来的吗？ Bù shì nǐ yào wǒ lái de ma？ Wasn’t it you who asked me to come? 3 need; take 这活儿要不了这么多人。 Zhè huór yàobuliǎo zhème duō rén. You don’t need so many people for this job. 这项任务要十天才能完成。 Zhè xiàng rènwu yào shí tiān cái néng wánchéng. It will take ten days to get the work done. 
verb 1 must; should; it is necessary (or imperative, essential) 借东西要还。 Jiè dōngxi yào huán. One should return what one borrows. 我要不要留下来？ Wǒ yào bù yào liú xià lái？ Shall I stay? 这个问题要仔细考虑。 Zhège wèntí yào zǐxì kǎolǜ. This question calls for careful consideration. 2 shall; will; be going to 要下雨了。 Yào xià yǔ le. It’s going to rain. 他快要回来了。 Tā kuàiyào huílai le. He will soon be back. 天要黑了, 快走吧。 Tiān yào hēi le, kuài zǒu ba. It’s getting dark. Let’s hurry up! 会议要到月底才能结束。 Huìyì yào dào yuèdǐ cái néng jiéshù. The conference will not end till the end of the month. 3 want to; wish to 他要学游泳。 Tā yào xué yóuyǒng. He wants to learn swimming. 我还有几句话要说。 Wǒ háiyǒu jǐ jù huà yào shuō. I’d like to say a few more words. 4 [in comparisons to indicate an estimate] 树荫底下比屋子里要凉快些。 shùyīn dǐxia bǐ wūzi lǐ yào liángkuai xiē. It is cooler under the tree than in the room. 
conjunction 1 if; suppose; in case 明天要下雨, 我们就不去了。 Míngtiān yào xiàyǔ, wǒmen jiù bù qù le. If it rains tomorrow, we won’t go. 他要来不了呢？ Tā yào láibuliǎo ne？ Suppose he can’t come? 我要赶不回来, 你替我说一声。 Wǒ yào gǎn bù huílai, nǐ tì wǒ shuō yī shēng. In case I can’t get back in time, please apologize for me. 这有什么可怕的, 要我就不怕。 Zhè yǒu shénme kěpà de, yào wǒ jiù bù pà. What is there to be afraid of? I wouldn’t be afraid if I were you. 2 [usu. with 就 or 就是] or; either... or... 要就去跳舞, 要就去听音乐, 别处我不去。 Yào jiù qù tiàowǔ,  yào jiù qù tīng yīnyuè, biéchù wǒ bù qù. Let’s go either to the dance or to the concert. I won’t go anywhere else.</defn>
            </entry>
            <dictref dictid="PACE" entryid="34253568"/>
            <catassign category="HSK 2012-2018/Level 2"/>
            <catassign category="100/Freq40"/>
        </card>
        <card language="chinese">
            <entry>
                <headword charset="sc">也</headword>
                <headword charset="tc">也</headword>
                <pron type="hypy" tones="numbers">ye3</pron>
                <defn>auxiliary classical 1 [at the end of a sentence, indicating an explanation or a judgment] 陈胜者, 阳城人也。(《史记》) Chén shèng zhě, yáng chéng rén yě. Chen Sheng was a native of Yangcheng. 何其毒也！ Héqídúyě! How pernicious! 2 [at the end of a question or rhetorical question] 何也？ Hé yě？ How is that? or Why so? 是可忍, 孰不可忍也？ Shì kě rěn, shú bùkě rěn yě? If this can be tolerated, what cannot? 3 [in the middle of a sentence, marking off a sentence element about which there is to be a statement] 大道之行也, 天下为公。(《礼记》) Dàdào zhī xíng yě, tiānxiàwéigōng. (《Lǐjì》) When the Great Tao prevailed, the whole world was one community. 
adverb 1 also; too; as well; either 你不去, 我也不去。 Nǐ bù qù, wǒ yě bù qù. If you’re not going, I’m not going either. 我妹妹也是售货员。 Wǒ mèimei yě shì shòuhuòyuán. My sister is a shop assistant too. 中国是一个社会主义国家, 也是一个发展中国家。 Zhōngguó shì yī ge shèhuìzhǔyì guójiā, yě shì yī ge fāzhǎnzhōng guójiā. China is a socialist country, and a developing country as well. 2 [for emphasis, often before a negative expression] 她一天假也没请过。 Tā yī tiān jià yě méi qǐng guò. She has never asked for leave, not even for a day. 他忙得连饭也顾不上吃。 Tā máng de lián fàn yě gù bù shàng chī. He is so busy that he can’t even stop for a meal. 3 [used correlatively with 虽然, 即使, etc.] still; yet 你不说我也知道。 Nǐ bù shuō wǒ yě zhīdao. You don’t have to tell me. I know already. 我虽然没见过, 也听人说过。 Wǒ suīrán méi jiàn guò, yě tīng rén shuō guò. I’ve heard about it, though I have never seen it. 我怎么想也想不起来。 Wǒ zěnme xiǎng yě xiǎng bù qǐlai. I simply couldn’t recall it however hard I tried. 4 [in a hesitant or guarded statement] 也只好这样了。 Yě zhǐhǎo zhèyàng le. We’ll have to leave it at that. 他的英语也还可以。 Tā de Yīngyǔ yě hái kěyǐ. His English is passable. 这袋土豆也就一百公斤。 Zhè dài tǔdòu yě jiù yībǎi gōngjīn. This sack of potatoes weighs a hundred kilos at most.</defn>
            </entry>
            <dictref dictid="PACE" entryid="34275840"/>
            <catassign category="HSK 2012-2018/Level 2"/>
            <catassign category="100/Freq40"/>
        </card>
        <card language="chinese">
            <entry>
                <headword charset="sc">着</headword>
                <headword charset="tc">著</headword>
                <pron type="hypy" tones="numbers">zhe5</pron>
                <defn>auxiliary 1 [added to a verb or adjective to indicate a continued action or state, often with the particle 呢 at the end of the sentence] 大门敞着。 Dàmén chǎngzhe. The gate is wide open. 雪正下着呢。 Xuě zhèng xià zhe ne. It’s snowing. 别站着, 坐下吧。 Bié zhànzhe, zuòxia ba. No need to stand, please sit down. 他穿着一身新衣服。 Tā chuānzhe yī shēn xīn yīfu. He is wearing new clothes. 夜深了, 屋里的灯却还亮着。 Yèshēn le, wū lǐ de dēng què hái liàng zhe. It was late at night, but the lights in the room were still on. 他们正谈着话呢, 请你在外头等几分钟吧。 Tāmen zhèng tán zhe huà ne, qǐng nǐ zài wàitou děng jǐ fēnzhōng ba. They are talking just now, please wait outside a few minutes. 2 [in sentences beginning with a place word, added to the verb to indicate a resultant state, the verb plus 着 having the force of “there is”] 墙上挂着一幅山水画。 Qiáng shàng guà zhe yī fú shānshuǐhuà. On the wall hangs a landscape painting. 桌上放着好些东西。 Zhuō shàng fàng zhe hǎoxiē dōngxi. There are a lot of things on the table. 3 [verb plus 着 placed before another verb, indicating an accompanying action or state] a [verb plus 着 serving as an adverbial modifier] 他爱吃着饭看报。 Tā ài chī zhe fàn kànbào. He likes to read the newspaper while eating. 他老低着头走路。 Tā lǎo dī zhe tóu zǒulù. He always walks with his head bent. 他正忙着准备考试。 Tā zhèng mángzhe zhǔnbèi kǎoshì. He is busy preparing for the examination. 孩子们急着要出去玩儿。 Háizi men jí zhe yào chūqu wánr. The children are in a hurry to go outside and play. 路不远, 咱们走着去吧。 Lù bù yuǎn, zánmen zǒu zhe qù ba. It’s quite near, let’s go on foot. 探险队冒着大雪上山。 Tànxiǎnduì mào zhe dàxuě shàngshān. The expedition climbed the mountain in spite of the heavy snow. b [verb plus 着 repeated, indicating that while one action is in progress another is expected] 她想着想着笑了起来。 Tā xiǎng zhe xiǎng zhe xiào le qǐlai. She thought for a while and then burst out laughing. 走着走着天色暗了下来。 Zǒu zhe zǒu zhe tiānsè àn le xiàlai. As we walked along, it began to grow dark. 4 [in imperative sentences, used after verbs or adjectives for emphasis, often with 点儿 added] 等着！ Děngzhe! Wait! 慢着！ Mànzhe! Hold it! 快着点儿。 Kuài zhe diǎnr. Hurry! 你听着。 Nǐ tīngzhe. Listen! 过马路看着点儿。 Guò mǎlù kànzhe diǎnr. Mind when you cross the street. 这事你记着点儿。 Zhè shì nǐ jì zhe diǎnr. Be sure to remember this. or Don’t forget! 5 [in forming a preposition] 向着 xiàngzhe towards 沿着马路 Yán zhe mǎlù along the road</defn>
            </entry>
            <dictref dictid="PACE" entryid="35946752"/>
            <catassign category="HSK 2012-2018/Level 2"/>
            <catassign category="100/Freq50"/>
        </card>
        <card language="chinese">
            <entry>
                <headword charset="sc">发</headword>
                <headword charset="tc">發</headword>
                <pron type="hypy" tones="numbers">fa1</pron>
                <defn>verb 1 send (out); issue; emit; give forth; shoot 发炮 fāpào fire shells 发传单 fā chuándān distribute leaflets 发传真 fā chuánzhēn send a fax 发电报 fā diànbào send a telegram 发工资 fā gōngzī pay out wages 发命令 fā mìnglìng issue an order 发信号 fā xìnhào give a signal 发电子邮件 fā diànzǐ yóujiàn send an email 发了三条新闻。 Fā le sān tiáo xīnwén. Three items of news have been released. 万箭齐发。 Wànjiànqífā. Ten thousand arrows shot at once. 2 utter; express 发一通议论 fā yī tòng yìlùn speak at length 3 come or bring into existence; generate; germinate See 20590592发电fa1dian4发电;20626432发芽fa1ya2 发芽 4 become; come to be 脸色发白 liǎnsè fā bái become pale; lose colour 肉发臭了。 Ròu fāchòu le. The meat smells a bit off. or The meat smells bad. 树叶发黄了。 Shùyè fā huáng le. The leaves are turning yellow. 5 (of foodstuffs) rise or expand when leavened or soaked 发海参 fā hǎishēn puff up dried sea cucumbers (by soaking them in water) 面发起来了。 Miàn fā qǐlai le. The dough has risen. 6 develop; expand See 20630016发育fa1yu4发育 7 open up; expose 揭发 jiēfā expose; unmask 8 feel; have a feeling 发麻 fāmá tingle 发痒 fāyǎng itch 嘴里发苦 Zuǐlǐ fākǔ have a bitter taste in the mouth 9 start; set out 车船齐发。 Chē chuán qí fā. All the boats and carts set out at the same time. 10 colloquial become rich; make a fortune 他做生意发了。 tā zuò shēngyifā le. He has made a large fortune in business. 11 show one&apos;s feelings See 20588544发愁fa1chou2发愁;20611584发怒fa1nu4 发怒;20624384发笑fa1xiao4 发笑 
measure word [for bullets and shells] 一发炮弹 Yī fā pàodàn one shell 两百发子弹 liǎngbǎi fā zǐdàn two hundred rounds of ammunition; two hundred cartridges</defn>
            </entry>
            <dictref dictid="PACE" entryid="20584448"/>
            <catassign category="HSK 2012-2018/Level 3"/>
            <catassign category="100/Freq50"/>
        </card>
        <card language="chinese">
            <entry>
                <headword charset="sc">分</headword>
                <headword charset="tc">分</headword>
                <pron type="hypy" tones="numbers">fen1</pron>
                <defn>verb 1 divide; separate; part (opp. 合) 分组讨论 fēnzǔ tǎolùn hold discussions in groups 分阶段实行 Fēn jiēduàn shíxíng carry out stage by stage 一年分四季。 Yī nián fēn sìjì. The year is divided into four seasons. 这药分三次吃。 Zhè yào fēn sān cì chī. This medicine is to be taken in three separate doses. 他的头发往右边分。 Tā de tóufa wǎng yòubianfēn. He parts his hair on the right side. 一条河把县城分成两半。 Yī tiáo hé bǎ xiànchéng fēn chéng liǎngbàn. A river divides the county town into two parts. 2 distribute; assign; allot 她分到了一套新房子。 Tā fēn dào le yī tào xīn fángzi. She has been allotted a new flat. 把这个任务分给我们吧。 Bǎ zhège rènwu fēn gěi wǒmen ba. Assign (or Give) this task to us, please. 音乐会的票都已经分完了。 Yīnyuèhuì de piào dōu yǐjing fēn wán le. The tickets for the concert have all been distributed. 大学毕业后, 他就分到外交部工作。 Dàxué bìyè hòu, tājiù fēn dào Wàijiāobù gōngzuò. After his graduation from college, he was assigned to work at the Foreign Ministry. 3 distinguish; differentiate 是非不分 shìfēibùfēn make no distinction between right and wrong 现在还分不出个胜负来。 Xiànzài hái fēn bù chū ge shèng-fù lái. It’s still quite impossible to tell who’ll win. 这对双胞胎长得一模一样, 简直分不出谁是谁。 Zhè duì shuāngbāotāi zhǎng de yīmúyīyàng, jiǎnzhí fēn bù chū shuí shì shuí. The twins look so much alike that you can hardly tell them apart. 
adjective branch (of an organization) 新华社上海分社 Xīnhuáshè Shànghǎi fēnshè the Shanghai Branch of the Xinhua News Agency 
measure word 1 fraction 约分 yuēfēn reduction of a fraction 2 [in spoken forms of fractions and percentages] 三分之一 sānfēn zhīyī one-third 十分之七 shífēn zhī qī seven-tenths 百分之四 bǎifēn zhī sì four per cent 3 one tenth (of certain units of the metric system) 4 fen (of the traditional system of weights and measures) a a traditional unit of length, equal to 0.01 chi (市尺), and equivalent to 0.333 centimetre or 0.131 inch b a traditional unit of weight, equal to 0.001 jin (市斤), and equivalent to 0.5 gram or 0.175 ounce c a traditional unit of area, equal to 0.1 mu (市亩) and equivalent to 0.667 acre or 79.73 square yards d a unit of weight equal to 0.1 qian (钱) or 0.01 liang (两) 5 fen (equal to one hundredth of a yuan (元)) 六元三角五分 liù yuán sānjiǎo wǔfēn 6.35 yuan 6 minute (equal to one sixtieth of an hour) 7 minute (equal to one sixtieth of a degree of angle or arc) 成 36 度 30分角 chéng 36 dù 30fēn jiǎo form an angle of 36 degrees 30 minutes (36°30′) 东经 129 度 15分 dōngjīng 129 dù 15 fēn 129 degrees 15 minutes (129°15′) east longitude 8 a unit of interest rate a 1% monthly interest 月利一分二厘. yuèlì yī fēn èr lí 1.2% monthly interest b 10% annual interest 年利一分二厘. niánlì yī fēn èr lí 12% annual interest 9 point; mark 六十分为及格。 Liùshí fēnwéi jígé. Sixty is the passing mark. 甲队罚球连得二分。 Jiǎ duì fáqiú lián de èrfēn. Team A scored two successive points by free throws. 他今天考试得了一百分。 Tā jīntiān kǎoshì déle yībǎi fēn. He got full marks in today’s exam. 10 [for nonphysical things] one-tenth 七分成绩, 三分错误 Qī fēn chéngjì, sānfēn cuòwù 70 per cent achievements, 30 per cent mistakes 他已经有三分醉了。 Tā yǐjing yǒu sānfēn zuì le. He’s a bit tipsy already. 我的牙痛好了几分。 Wǒ de yátòng hǎo le jǐ fēn. My toothache has been partly relieved. 这消息使我多了一分希望。 Zhè xiāoxi shǐ wǒ duō le yī fēn xīwàng. The news raised my hopes a little.</defn>
            </entry>
            <dictref dictid="PACE" entryid="20944128"/>
            <catassign category="HSK 2012-2018/Level 3"/>
            <catassign category="100/Freq80"/>
        </card>
        <card language="chinese">
            <entry>
                <headword charset="sc">为</headword>
                <headword charset="tc">為</headword>
                <pron type="hypy" tones="numbers">wei4</pron>
                <defn>preposition 1 in the interest of; for 为大多数人谋利益 Wèi dàduōshù rén móu lìyì work in the interests of the vast majority 2 because of 为胜利而欢呼 Wèi shènglì ér huānhū hail a victory 为我们的友谊干杯！ Wèi wǒmen de yǒuyì gānbēi! A toast to our friendship! 3 for the purpose of; for the sake of 为方便起见 wèi fāngbiàn qǐjiàn for the sake of convenience 不为名, 不为利 bù wèi míng, bù wèi lì seek no personal fame or gain 让我们为实现这一宏伟目标而共同努力。 Ràng wǒmen wèi shíxiàn zhè yī hóngwěi mùbiāo ér gòngtóng nǔlì. Let us strive together to attain this splendid goal. 4 to; towards 他为我送来一份请帖。 Tā wèi wǒ sòng lái yī fèn qǐngtiě. He’s sent me an invitation. 且为诸君言之。 Qiě wèi zhūjūn yán zhī. I’ll let you know. 
verb literary stand for; support</defn>
            </entry>
            <dictref dictid="PACE" entryid="32267008"/>
            <catassign category="HSK 2012-2018/Level 3"/>
            <catassign category="100/Freq20"/>
        </card>
        <card language="chinese">
            <entry>
                <headword charset="sc">用</headword>
                <headword charset="tc">用</headword>
                <pron type="hypy" tones="numbers">yong4</pron>
                <defn>noun 1 expenses; outlay See 23655168家用jia1yong4家用;26009344零用ling2yong4零用 2 usefulness; use 没什么用 méishénme yòng rather useless 有点儿用 yǒudiǎnr yòng be of some use 3 (Yòng) a surname 
verb 1 use; employ; apply; consume 酒精常用作溶剂。 Jiǔjīng chángyòng zuò róngjì. Alcohol is often used as a solvent. 你会不会用计算机？ Nǐ huì bù huì yòng jìsuànjī？ Do you know how to operate a computer? 你应该把主要精力用在学习上。 Nǐ yīnggāi bǎ zhǔyào jīnglì yòng zài xuéxí shàng. You should devote your chief energies to your studies. 2 [usu. in the negative] need 不用担心。 Bùyòng dānxīn. Don’t worry. 不用开灯。 Bù yòng kāi dēng. There’s no need to turn on the light. 3 courteous eat; drink 请用茶。 Qǐng yòng chá. Won’t you have some tea, please? 
preposition with 用火烤 yòng huǒ kǎo roast over the fire 用手掰 Yòng shǒu bāi break with one’s hands 用水煮 yòng shuǐ zhǔ boil in water 用五十八秒钟跑完全程 yòng wǔshíbā miǎo zhōng pǎo wán quánchéng run the course in 58 seconds 用针刺麻醉做外科手术 yòng zhēncì mázuì zuò wàikē shǒushù employ acupuncture anaesthesia in surgery 
conjunction literary [usu. in letters] hence; therefore 用特函达。 Yòng tè hán dá. Hence this letter.</defn>
            </entry>
            <dictref dictid="PACE" entryid="34931200"/>
            <catassign category="HSK 2012-2018/Level 3"/>
            <catassign category="100/Freq60"/>
        </card>
        <card language="chinese">
            <entry>
                <headword charset="sc">只</headword>
                <headword charset="tc">只</headword>
                <pron type="hypy" tones="numbers">zhi3</pron>
                <defn>adverb only; just; merely 只剩一个了。 Zhǐ shèng yī ge le. There is only one left. 我只想问一个问题。 Wǒ zhǐ xiǎng wèn yī ge wèntí. I have just one question. 这只是个时间问题。 Zhè zhǐ shìge shíjiān wèntí. It is merely a question of time. 我们这车只能带三个人。 Wǒmen zhè chē zhǐ néng dài sān ge rén. We can only take three people in our car. 屋子里只老王一个人。 Wūzi lǐ zhǐ lǎo wáng yī ge rén. Old Wang was alone in the room. 只那块地就打了八百斤小麦。 Zhǐ nà kuài dì jiù dǎ le bābǎi jīn xiǎomài. That plot alone yielded 800 jin of wheat.</defn>
            </entry>
            <dictref dictid="PACE" entryid="36225792"/>
            <catassign category="HSK 2012-2018/Level 3"/>
            <catassign category="100/Freq100"/>
            <catassign category="LP1"/>
        </card>
        <card language="chinese">
            <entry>
                <headword charset="sc">种</headword>
                <headword charset="tc">種</headword>
                <pron type="hypy" tones="numbers">zhong3</pron>
                <defn>noun 1 biology species 本地种 běndì zhǒng endemic (or local) species 外地种 wàidì zhǒng exotic (or foreign) species 老虎是猫科的一种。 Lǎohǔ shì māo kē de yī zhǒng. The tiger belongs to the cat family. 2 race; stock See 23077888黄种huang2zhong3黄种;17052160白种bai2zhong3白种 3 branch; division; kind; sort; type 工种 gōngzhǒng work category; type of work (in production) 语种 yǔzhǒng languages; language type 4 seed; strain; breed 麦种 Mài zhǒng wheat seeds 这水稻是什么种？ Zhè shuǐdào shì shénme zhǒng？ Which variety of rice is this? 5 guts; grit 没种 méizhǒng gutless; cowardly See 35119104有种you3zhong3有种 
measure word kind; sort; type 各种仪器 gèzhǒng yíqì all kinds of instruments 这种论调 zhèzhǒng lùndiào this sort of argument 一种现象 yī zhǒng xiànxiàng a phenomenon 四十种钢材 sìshí zhǒng gāngcái forty types of rolled steel 他有(一)种以前从未有过的感觉。 Tā yǒu yī zhǒng yǐqián cóngwèiyǒuguò de gǎnjué. He felt something he’d never felt before.</defn>
            </entry>
            <dictref dictid="PACE" entryid="36427776"/>
            <catassign category="HSK 2012-2018/Level 3"/>
            <catassign category="100/Freq60"/>
        </card>
        <card language="chinese">
            <entry>
                <headword charset="sc">当</headword>
                <headword charset="tc">當</headword>
                <pron type="hypy" tones="numbers">dang1</pron>
                <defn>verb 1 work as; serve as; be 选他当组长 Xuǎn tā dāng zǔzhǎng elect him group leader 我长大要当飞行员。 Wǒ zhǎngdà yào dāng fēixíngyuán. I want to be a pilot when I grow up. 2 bear; accept; deserve 敢做敢当 gǎnzuògǎndāng dare to act and to take the consequences 我可当不起这样的夸奖。 Wǒ kě dāng bù qǐ zhèyàng de kuājiǎng. I just don’t deserve such praise. 3 direct; manage; be in charge of See 19645696当家dang1jia1当家 4 [as aux.] ought to; should; must 能省的就省, 当用的还是得用。 Néng shěng de jiù shěng, dāng yòng de háishi dé yòng. Save what you can, but use what you must. 5 literary hold back; block See 31200768螳臂当车tang2bi4dang1che1螳臂当车 
adjective equal See 26675200门当户对men2dang1hu4dui4门当户对 
preposition 1 in sb.&apos;s presence; to sb.&apos;s face 咱当着大家谈一谈。 Zán dāng zhe dàjiā tán yī tán. Let’s speak out in the presence of everyone. 2 just at (a time or place) 当莫扎特四岁时, 就开始写小步舞曲。 dāng mò zhā tè sì suìshí, jiù kāishǐ xiě xiǎobù wǔqǔ. When only four, Mozart was composing minuets. 
onomatopoeia sound of a gong or a bell 当当的钟声 Dāng dāng de zhōngshēng the tolling of a bell 
noun literary end 瓦当 wǎdāng eaves tile</defn>
            </entry>
            <dictref dictid="PACE" entryid="19640064"/>
            <catassign category="HSK 2012-2018/Level 4"/>
            <catassign category="100/Freq80"/>
        </card>
        <card language="chinese">
            <entry>
                <headword charset="sc">而</headword>
                <headword charset="tc">而</headword>
                <pron type="hypy" tones="numbers">er2</pron>
                <defn>conjunction 1 and; as well as 伟大而艰巨的任务 wěidà ér jiānjù de rènwu great and arduous task 2 and yet; but; while on the other hand 有其名而无其实 Yǒu qí míng ér wú qíshí in name but not in reality 你喜爱体育运动, 而我呢, 情愿看书。 Nǐ xǐ&apos;ài tǐyù yùndòng,  ér wǒ ne, qíngyuàn kàn shū. You like sports, while I’d rather read. 这里的气候有利于种小麦, 而不利于种水稻。 Zhèlǐ de qìhòu yǒulì yú zhòng xiǎomài, ér bù lìyú zhòng shuǐdào. The climate here is favourable to the growth of wheat but unfavourable to the growth of rice. 3 so that; in order to 不要因失败而灰心, 也不要因成功而骄傲。 Bùyào yīn shībài ér huīxīn, yě bùyào yīn chénggōng ér jiāo&apos;ào. Don’t be discouraged by failure or get dizzy with success. 4 [with 由, 从, 自,  etc.] to 由南而北 Yóu nán ér běi from south to north 自远而近 zìyuǎn&apos;érjìn approach from a distance 由童年而少年, 而壮年 yóu tóngnián ér shàonián, ér zhuàngnián from childhood to teenage, then to middle age 5 [connecting an adverbial element to a verb] 匆匆而去 cōngcōng&apos;érqù leave in haste 盘旋而上 pánxuán ér shàng spiral up 顺流而下 shùnliú&apos;érxià go down the stream 6 [between a subject and a predicate expressing a condition, to be followed by a clause indicating result] if 作家而不深入群众, 就写不出好作品。 Zuòjiā ér bù shēnrù qúnzhòng, jiù xiěbuchū hǎo zuòpǐn. If a writer does not go deep among the masses, he cannot expect to turn out good writings.</defn>
            </entry>
            <dictref dictid="PACE" entryid="20530176"/>
            <catassign category="HSK 2012-2018/Level 4"/>
            <catassign category="100/Freq40"/>
        </card>
        <card language="chinese">
            <entry>
                <headword charset="sc">行</headword>
                <headword charset="tc">行</headword>
                <pron type="hypy" tones="numbers">xing2</pron>
                <defn>noun behaviour; conduct 品行 pǐnxíng moral conduct 言行 yánxíng words and deeds 
verb 1 literary go; walk; travel 非洲之行 Fēizhōu zhī xíng a trip to Africa 日行百里 rì xíng bǎi lǐ cover a hundred li a day 日行三千步 rì xíng sānqiān bù walk three thousand steps a day (for exercise) 儿行千里母担忧。 Ér xíng qiān lǐ mǔ dānyōu. When children travel far from home, mothers never stop worrying. 2 be current; circulate 发行 fāxíng issue; publish; distribute; put on sale 3 do; perform; carry out 简便易行 jiǎnbiàn yìxíng simple and easy to do 4 [before a disyllabic verb, indicating the performance of some action] 即行通知 jí xíng tōngzhī notify sb. at once 另行安排 lìngxíng ānpái make separate arrangements 5 be all right; will do 没有铅丝, 用绳子也行。 Méiyǒu qiānsī, yòng shéngzi yě xíng. If there is no wire, a cord will do. 你替我到邮局跑一趟, 行吗？——行！ Nǐ tì wǒ dào yóujú pǎo yī tàng, xíng ma？ -- xíng! Would you run over to the post office for me? — OK! or All right! 在快车道上骑车可不行。 Zài kuàichēdào shàng qíchē kě bùxíng. Cycling along the motorway is not allowed. 咱们走着去, 行不行？ Zánmen zǒuzhe qù, xíng bù xíng？ Will it be all right if we go on foot? 6 (of medicine) take effect 感觉药性已行 Gǎnjué yàoxìng yǐ xíng feel that medicine is taking effect 
adjective 1 temporary; makeshift See 33510656行营xing2ying2行营;33511936行灶xing2zao4 行灶 2 capable; competent 不要认为只有自己才行。 Bùyào rènwéi zhǐyǒu zìjǐ cái xíng. Don’t think you’re the only capable one. 老王, 你真行！ Lǎo wáng, nǐ zhēn xíng! Lao Wang, you are really terrific (or something great)! 你看他干这工作行吗？ Nǐ kàn tā gàn zhè gōngzuò xíng ma？ Do you think he is up to it? 
adverb literary soon 别来行复四年。 Bié lái xíng fù sì nián. It is four years since we parted.</defn>
            </entry>
            <dictref dictid="PACE" entryid="33487872"/>
            <catassign category="HSK 2012-2018/Level 4"/>
            <catassign category="100/Freq60"/>
        </card>
        <card language="chinese">
            <entry>
                <headword charset="sc">以</headword>
                <headword charset="tc">以</headword>
                <pron type="hypy" tones="numbers">yi3</pron>
                <defn>preposition 1 with; by means of 以守为攻 yǐ shǒu wéi gōng use defence as a means of offence 以市场为导向 yǐ shìchǎng wéi dǎoxiàng guided by the market; market-oriented 以天下为己任 yǐ tiān xià wéi jǐ rèn take the destiny of one’s country as one’s own responsibility 以质量求发展 yǐ zhìliàng qiú fāzhǎn strategy of development through quality 以姓氏笔画为序  yǐ xìngshì bǐhuà wéi xù in order of the number of strokes in their surnames 以我之长, 攻敌之短 yǐ wǒ zhī cháng, gōng dí zhī duǎn utilize our strong points to attack the enemy’s weak points 喻之以理 Yù zhī yǐ lǐ reason with sb.; try to make sb. see reason 赠以鲜花 zèng yǐ xiānhuā present sb. with a bouquet 2 according to 以此类推 yǐcǐlèituī on the analogy of this 以时启闭 yǐshíqǐbì open and close according to schedule 以到达先后为序 yǐ dàodá xiān-hòu wéi xù in order of arrival 3 because of 不以失败自馁, 不以成功自满 bù yǐ shībài zìněi, bù yǐ chénggōng zìmǎn not lose heart because of failure nor feel conceited because of success 何以知之？ Héyǐ zhī zhī？ How do you know? 4 literary at (a certain time); on (a fixed date) 我以三月一日返。 wǒ yǐ Sānyuè yī rì fǎn. I returned on March the first. 
conjunction 1 in order to; so as to 以示区别 yǐ shì qūbié so as to distinguish this from other cases 以应急需 Yǐ yìng jíxū in order to answer an urgent need 2 literary and; as well as 城高以厚。 Chéng gāo yǐ hòu. The city wall is high and thick. 淅沥以潇飒 Xīlì yǐ xiāo sà raindrops pattering and wind rustling 
preposition [before certain localizers to form compound localizers] 长江以北 Cháng Jiāng yǐ běi north of the Yangtze River 
noun abbreviation Israel 以军 yǐjūn Israeli army</defn>
            </entry>
            <dictref dictid="PACE" entryid="34540800"/>
            <catassign category="HSK 2012-2018/Level 4"/>
            <catassign category="100/Freq40"/>
        </card>
        <card language="chinese">
            <entry>
                <headword charset="sc">之</headword>
                <headword charset="tc">之</headword>
                <pron type="hypy" tones="numbers">zhi1</pron>
                <defn>verb literary go; leave for 由京之渝 Yóu jīng zhī yú leave Beijing for Chongqing 君将何之？ Jūn jiāng hé zhī？ Where are you bound for? 
pronoun literary 1 [in place of an objective noun or pronoun] 将如之何？ Jiāng rú zhī hé？ What is to be done? 影片情节十分悲惨, 观众无不为之感动。 Yǐngpiàn qíngjié shífēn bēicǎn, guānzhòng wúbù wèi zhī gǎndòng. The film was so sad that everyone was moved. 2 [in certain set phrases without definite designation] 手之舞之, 足之蹈之 Shǒu zhī wǔ zhī, zú zhī dǎo zhī dance with joy 我们三个人我最年长, 李次之, 张又次之。 Wǒmen sān ge rén wǒ zuì niánzhǎng,  lǐ cìzhī, zhāng yòu cì zhī. Of the three of us, I am the eldest, Li is younger, and Zhang is the youngest. 3 this; that 之子于归。 Zhīzǐyúguī. The maiden goes to her future home. 
auxiliary 1 [between an attribute and the word it modifies] 宝中之宝 Bǎozhōngzhībǎo the treasure of treasures; the most precious 抱歉之至 bàoqiàn zhī zhì awfully sorry 得意之极 déyì zhī jí very pleased with oneself 感激之至 gǎnjī zhī zhì deeply grateful 三分之一 sānfēn zhīyī one-third 一水之隔 yīshuǐzhīgé separated only by a river 以我之长, 攻敌之短 yǐ wǒ zhī cháng, gōng dí zhī duǎn utilize our strong points to attack the enemy at his weak points 原因之一 yuányīn zhīyī one of the reasons 钟鼓之声 Zhōng-gǔ zhī shēng the sound of drums and bells 百分之八十 bǎifēn zhī bāshí eighty per cent 非常之需要 fēicháng zhī xūyào highly necessary 非常之正确 fēicháng zhī zhèngquè absolutely right 急群众之急 jí qúnzhòng zhī jí eager to meet the needs of the populace 五千年之久 wǔqiān nián zhī jiǔ as long as five thousand years 不胜荣幸之至 bù shèng róngxìng zhī zhì feel greatly honoured 我之所以讨厌他是因为他的嘴太贫。 Wǒ zhīsuǒyǐ tǎoyàn tā shì yīnwèi tā de zuǐ tài pín. I dislike him because he is too garrulous. 弦乐器是指琵琶, 二胡, 小提琴之类。 xiányuèqì shì zhǐ pípa, èrhú, xiǎotíqín zhī lèi. Stringed instruments refer to the pipa, erhu, and violin, etc. 2 literary [between the subject and the predicate in an S-P structure so as to make it nominalized] 如因势利导, 则如水之就下, 极为自然。 Rú yīnshìlìdǎo,  zé rú shuǐ zhī jiù xià, jíwéi zìrán. If we guide the matter along their course of development, it will proceed as naturally as water flows downwards.</defn>
            </entry>
            <dictref dictid="PACE" entryid="36121088"/>
            <catassign category="HSK 2012-2018/Level 4"/>
            <catassign category="100/Freq50"/>
        </card>
        <card language="chinese">
            <entry>
                <headword charset="sc">方</headword>
                <headword charset="tc">方</headword>
                <pron type="hypy" tones="numbers">fang1</pron>
                <defn>noun 1 square 这块板子是方的。 Zhè kuài bǎnzi shì fāng de. This is a square board. 2 mathematics involution; power 二的四次方是十六。 Èr de sì cì fāng shì shíliù. The fourth power of 2 is 16. 三的三次方是二十七。 Sān de sān cì fāng shì èrshíqī. The third power (or cube) of 3 is 27. 3 abbreviation (usu. 平方米或立方米) square or cubic (usu. square or cubic metre) 一方木材 yī fāng mùcái a cubic metre of lumber 铺地板十五方 pū dìbǎn shíwǔ fāng lay 15 square metres of floorboards 4 (Fāng) a surname 
adjective upright; honest See 20790528方正fang1zheng4方正 
measure word [for square things] 三方图章 Sān fāng túzhāng three seals 一方手帕 yī fāng shǒupà a handkerchief 
noun 1 direction 东方 dōngfāng east 前方 qiánfāng ahead; in front 2 side; party 我方 wǒfāng our side 3 place; region; locality 远方 yuǎnfāng distant place 
noun 1 method; way 治疗有方 zhìliáo yǒu fāng treat with proper method 2 prescription 这方儿专治腰痛。 Zhè fāngr zhuān zhì yāo tòng. This prescription is especially good for backaches. 
adverb literary 1 just when; at the time when See 20781824方今fang1jin1方今 2 only; just 年方二十 Nián fāng èrshí be just twenty years old</defn>
            </entry>
            <dictref dictid="PACE" entryid="20774400"/>
            <catassign category="HSK 2012-2018/Level 5"/>
            <catassign category="100/Freq70"/>
        </card>
        <card language="chinese">
            <entry>
                <headword charset="sc">所</headword>
                <headword charset="tc">所</headword>
                <pron type="hypy" tones="numbers">suo3</pron>
                <defn>noun 1 place 住所 zhùsuǒ dwelling place; residence 2 office; bureau; institute 指挥所 zhǐhuīsuǒ command post 3 dated troop station in the Ming Dynasty 
measure word [for houses, schools, hospitals, etc.] 两所学校 liǎng suǒ xuéxiào two schools 一所房子 Yī suǒ fángzi a house 这所医院 zhè suǒ yīyuàn this hospital 
auxiliary literary 1 [noun or pronoun＋所＋verb] a [with 的 to modify a noun] 我所认识的人 wǒ suǒ rènshi de rén the people I know 大家所提的意见 dàjiā suǒ tí de yìjian the opinions various people put forward b [with 的 as a noun] 他所说的未必确实。 Tā suǒ shuō de wèibì quèshí. What he says is not necessarily true. 我所知道的就这些。 Wǒ suǒ zhīdao de jiù zhèxiē. That’s all I know. c [as a noun without 的, esp. when the verb is monosyllabic] 所到之处 suǒdàozhīchù wherever one goes 所见所闻 suǒjiànsuǒwén what one sees and hears 尽我所能 jìn wǒ suǒ néng do all I can 据你所说 jù nǐ suǒ shuō from what you say 2 [所＋verb] a [with 的 to modify a noun] 所需的费用 suǒ xū de fèiyong necessary expenses 所用的方法 suǒ yòng de fāngfǎ the methods which are used b [with 的 as a noun] 所需的并不多。 Suǒ xū de bìng bù duō. What is needed is not much. 我们所考虑的正是这一点。 wǒmensuǒ kǎolǜ de zhèngshì zhè yīdiǎn. That’s just what we have under consideration. c [as a noun without 的, esp. in set phrases in which the verb is monosyllabic] 各尽所能 gèjìnsuǒnéng from each according to his ability 3 [为 or 被＋ noun or pronoun ＋所＋ verb, expressing a passive meaning] 为人所笑 wéi rén suǒ xiào be laughed at by other people 被表面现象所迷惑 bèi biǎomiàn xiànxiàng suǒ míhuo be misled by outward appearances 4 [所＋ verb used as the object of 有 or 无] a [as the object of 有] 有所创造 yǒusuǒ chuàngzào create something or other 有所准备 yǒusuǒ zhǔnbèi be prepared in some way or other b [as the object of 无, esp. in set phrases] 无所准备 wú suǒ zhǔnbèi need do nothing in preparation for it 无所用心 wúsuǒyòngxīn not give serious thought to anything</defn>
            </entry>
            <dictref dictid="PACE" entryid="31021568"/>
            <catassign category="HSK 2012-2018/Level 5"/>
            <catassign category="100/Freq60"/>
        </card>
        <card language="chinese">
            <entry>
                <headword charset="sc">不了</headword>
                <headword charset="tc">不了</headword>
                <pron type="hypy" tones="numbers">bu4liao3</pron>
                <defn>verb [after a verb plus 个] without end; non-stop 一天到晚忙个不了 yī tiān dào wǎn máng ge bùliǎo busy from morning till night 大雨下个不了。 Dàyǔ xià ge bùliǎo. The rain kept pouring down.</defn>
            </entry>
            <dictref dictid="PACE" entryid="17955840"/>
            <catassign category="100/Freq10"/>
        </card>
        <card language="chinese">
            <entry>
                <headword charset="sc">们</headword>
                <headword charset="tc">們</headword>
                <pron type="hypy" tones="numbers">men5</pron>
                <defn>affix 1 [after personal pronoun or a noun referring to a person to form the plural] 工人们 gōngrén men workers 同志们 tóngzhì men comrades 女士们, 先生们 nǚshì men, xiānsheng men ladies and gentlemen 2 [in personification after a noun referring to an object or an animal to form the plural] 满天的星星们眨着眼睛。 Mǎn tiān de xīngxing men zhǎ zhe yǎnjing. All the stars were blinking. 奶奶管我们叫小燕子们。 Nǎinai guǎn wǒmen jiào xiǎoyànzi men. Grandma calls us “little swallows”. 3 [after the name of a person to mean people of the same kind, or to mean his or her associates] 希特勒们 Xītèlè men the likes of Hitler</defn>
            </entry>
            <dictref dictid="PACE" entryid="26695936"/>
            <catassign category="100/Freq20"/>
        </card>
        <card language="chinese">
            <entry>
                <headword charset="sc">中</headword>
                <headword charset="tc">中</headword>
                <pron type="hypy" tones="numbers">zhong1</pron>
                <defn>noun 1 centre; middle 冀中 jì zhōng central Hebei 上, 中, 下 shàng zhōng xià upper, middle, lower 2 (Zhōng) abbreviation China 中日友好关系 zhōng rì yǒuhǎo guānxi friendship between Japan and China 3 in; among; amidst 记在心中 jì zài xīnzhōng keep in mind; remember 跳入水中 tiào rù shuǐzhōng jump into the water 在修建中 zài xiūjiàn zhōng being built; under construction 4 middle; mid 月中 yuèzhōng middle of a month 5 medium; intermediate See 36364544中号zhong1hao4中号 6 mean; halfway between two extremes See 30262784适中shi4zhong1适中 7 intermediary 作中 zuòzhōng act as an intermediary 8 (Zhōng) a surname 
verb fit for; good for See 36371200中看zhong1kan4中看 
adjective dialect all right; OK 中不中？ Zhōng bu zhōng？ Is this all right? 这办法中！ Zhè bànfǎ zhōng! This works!</defn>
            </entry>
            <dictref dictid="PACE" entryid="36348160"/>
            <catassign category="100/Freq20"/>
        </card>
        <card language="chinese">
            <entry>
                <headword charset="sc">国</headword>
                <headword charset="tc">國</headword>
                <pron type="hypy" tones="numbers">guo2</pron>
                <defn>noun 1 country; nation; state 大国 dàguó a big country 强国 qiángguó a powerful nation 诸侯国 zhūhóu guó feudal states 保家卫国 bǎojiāwèiguó protect our homes and defend our country 利国利民 lìguólìmín benefit both country and people; good for the country and for the people 2 best of the nation See 22188288国手guo2shou3国手;22186496国色guo2se4国色 3 abbreviation Kuomintang (KMT) 国共两党 Guó Gòngliǎngdǎng KMT and CPC 4 (Guó) a surname 
adjective 1 of the state; national See 22161408国花guo2hua1国花 2 of our country; Chinese See 22161664国画guo2hua4国画</defn>
            </entry>
            <dictref dictid="PACE" entryid="22154752"/>
            <catassign category="100/Freq20"/>
        </card>
        <card language="chinese">
            <entry>
                <headword charset="sc">地</headword>
                <headword charset="tc">地</headword>
                <pron type="hypy" tones="numbers">de5</pron>
                <defn>auxiliary [after an adverbial phrase] 实事求是地处理问题 Shíshìqiúshì de chǔlǐ wèntí handle problems in a practical and realistic way 天渐渐地冷了。 Tiān jiànjiàn de lěng le. The weather is getting cold.</defn>
            </entry>
            <dictref dictid="PACE" entryid="19779328"/>
            <catassign category="100/Freq40"/>
        </card>
        <card language="chinese">
            <entry>
                <headword charset="sc">时</headword>
                <headword charset="tc">時</headword>
                <pron type="hypy" tones="numbers">shi2</pron>
                <defn>noun 1 time; fixed time 按时 ànshí on time 2 long period of time; times; days 古时 gǔshí ancient times 3 season 农时 nóngshí farming season 四时 sìshí four seasons 4 time of day; hour; o&apos;clock 上午八时 Shàngwǔ bā shí at 8 o’clock in the morning; at 8 a.m. 5 current; present See 30083584时下shi2xia4时下 6 opportunity; chance 待时而动 dàishí&apos;érdòng bide one’s time 7 linguistics tense 过去时 guòqùshí past tense 8 (Shí) a surname 
adverb now and then; occasionally; from time to time 时有发生 shíyǒu fāshēng occur from time to time</defn>
            </entry>
            <dictref dictid="PACE" entryid="30067456"/>
            <catassign category="100/Freq40"/>
        </card>
        <card language="chinese">
            <entry>
                <headword charset="sc">出</headword>
                <headword charset="tc">齣</headword>
                <pron type="hypy" tones="numbers">chu1</pron>
                <defn>measure word [for operas or plays] 一出戏 yī chū xì an opera; a play</defn>
            </entry>
            <dictref dictid="PACE" entryid="18843904"/>
            <catassign category="100/Freq40"/>
        </card>
        <card language="chinese">
            <entry>
                <headword charset="sc">可</headword>
                <headword charset="tc">可</headword>
                <pron type="hypy" tones="numbers">ke3</pron>
                <defn>verb 1 approve 认可 rènkě recognize 许可 xǔkě permit 2  a [as auxiliary] be willing to; be ready to 可干 kěgàn be willing to do hard work 可虚心接受意见 kě xūxīn jiēshòu yìjian be ready to listen to criticism with an open mind b dialect often; tending to 这几天可下雨。 Zhè jǐ tiān kě xià yǔ. It rained a lot these past few days. 北京可游的地方不少。 Běijīng kě yóu de dìfang bùshǎo. There are quite a few places worth visiting in Beijing. 
adverb literary about 年可二十 nián kě èrshí be aged about twenty 重可千斤 Zhòng kě qiān jīn weigh about a thousand jin 
preposition dialect [followed by 着] to the limit of; go as far as possible 可着嗓门儿哭 kě zhe sǎngménr kū cry at the top of one’s lungs (or voice) 就这么多钱, 你可着用吧。 jiù zhème duō qián, nǐ kě zháoyòng ba. You’ll have to make do with the money available. 
conjunction but; yet; however 劳动很艰苦, 可大家干劲十足。 Láodòng hěn jiānkǔ, kě dàjiā gànjìn shízú. It was hard work, but everybody went at it with a will. 都这么说, 可谁见过呢？ Dōu zhème shuō, kě shuí jiàn guò ne？ So they say, but who has ever actually seen it? 
adverb 1 colloquial [for emphasis] 你可来了！ Nǐ kě lái le! You’re here at last! 他可没说过这话。 Tā kě méi shuō guò zhè huà. He never saidthat. 你可不能粗心大意啊。 Nǐ kě bù néng cūxīndàyì a. You must not be careless. 2 [in a question for emphasis] 这话可是真的？ Zhè huà kě shì zhēn de？ Is that really true? 你可曾跟他谈过这个问题？ Nǐ kě céng gēn tā tán guò zhège wèntí？ Did you ever talk it over with him? 
verb fit; suit See 24967168可心ke3xin1可心;71220138可口儿ke3kou3r5 可口儿</defn>
            </entry>
            <dictref dictid="PACE" entryid="24946688"/>
            <catassign category="100/Freq40"/>
        </card>
        <card language="chinese">
            <entry>
                <headword charset="sc">生</headword>
                <headword charset="tc">生</headword>
                <pron type="hypy" tones="numbers">sheng1</pron>
                <defn>1 to be born 2 to give birth 3 life 4 to grow 5 raw 6 uncooked 7 student</defn>
            </entry>
            <dictref dictid="PCED" entryid="11448576"/>
            <catassign category="100/Freq40"/>
        </card>
        <card language="chinese">
            <entry>
                <headword charset="sc">子</headword>
                <headword charset="tc">子</headword>
                <pron type="hypy" tones="numbers">zi5</pron>
                <defn>affix 1 [added to some nouns or noun morphemes] 乱子 luànzi trouble; mess 帽子 màozi hat 胖子 pàngzi fat person 旗子 qízi flag 推子 tuīzi hair clipper 2 [added to certain measure words] 这档子事 zhè dàngzi shì this matter; this business 来了一伙子人。 Lái le yī huǒ zi rén. A group of people arrived. 我一下子想不起他的名字。 Wǒ yīxiàzi xiǎng bù qǐ tā de míngzi. I can’t recall his name at the moment.</defn>
            </entry>
            <dictref dictid="PACE" entryid="36809472"/>
            <catassign category="100/Freq40"/>
        </card>
        <card language="chinese">
            <entry>
                <headword charset="sc">于</headword>
                <headword charset="tc">於</headword>
                <pron type="hypy" tones="numbers">yu2</pron>
                <defn>preposition 1 [indicating time or place] in; on; at 生于上海 shēngyú Shànghǎi born in Shanghai 驰名于全世界 chímíng yú quánshìjiè be famous throughout the world; be of world renown 就学于北京大学 jiù xué yú Běijīng Dàxué study at Beijing University 来信于十五日收到。 Láixìn yú shíwǔ rì shōudào. Your letter was received on the 15th. 此项工程将于三年内完成。 Cǐ xiàng gōngchéng jiāng yú sān nián nèi wánchéng. This project is to be completed within three years. 第一次世界大战爆发于一九一四年。 Dì-yī cì shìjiè dàzhàn bàofā yú yī jiǔyīsì nián. The First World War broke out in 1914. 2 [indicating direction] toward; to 求助于人 qiúzhùyúrén ask people for help 热衷于集邮 rèzhōng yú jíyóu be keen on stamp collecting 3 [indicating giving or yielding to sb.] to; onto 腐朽的势力让位于新生的势力。 Fǔxiǔ de shìli ràngwèi yú xīn shēng de shìli. Decaying forces give way to new rising forces. 4 with regard to; concerning; to 有利于提高产量 Yǒulì yú tígāo chǎnliàng be conducive to higher yields 操之过急, 于事无补。 Cāozhīguòjí, yúshìwúbǔ. It would be of no avail to act with undue haste. 这样于你自己不利。 Zhèyàng yú nǐ zìjǐ bùlì. It won’t do you any good. 5 [indicating beginning or origin] from 黄河发源于青海。 Huáng Hé fā yuányú Qīnghǎi. The Yellow River rises in Qinghai Province. 认识来源于实践。 Rènshi láiyuányú shíjiàn. Knowledge comes from practice. 6 [indicating comparison] than 不少于五千人 Bù shǎoyú wǔqiān rén no less than 5,000 people 友谊贵于黄金。 Yǒuyì guì yú huángjīn. Friendship is more precious than gold. 金星略小于地球。 Jīnxīng lüè xiǎoyú dìqiú. Venus is a little smaller than the earth. 7 [indicating the doer of an action] by 见笑于人 Jiànxiào yú rén be laughed at (by others) 主队败于客队。 Zhǔduì bài yú kèduì. The home team was defeated by the visiting team. 
affix [after a verb or an adjective] 属于 shǔyú belong to 勇于 yǒngyú have the courage to; dare to 至于 zhìyú as for</defn>
            </entry>
            <dictref dictid="PACE" entryid="35155456"/>
            <catassign category="100/Freq50"/>
        </card>
        <card language="chinese">
            <entry>
                <headword charset="sc">自</headword>
                <headword charset="tc">自</headword>
                <pron type="hypy" tones="numbers">zi4</pron>
                <defn>pronoun self; oneself; one&apos;s own 自顾自 zìgùzì each for himself 自打耳光 zìdǎ ěrguāng slap one’s own face; contradict oneself 
adverb certainly; of course; naturally 自当努力 zì dāng nǔlì will certainly do one’s best 两人久别重逢, 自有许多话说。 Liǎng rén jiǔbiéchóngféng, zì yǒu xǔduō huà shuō. Naturally they had a lot to say to each other after such a long separation. 现在多用功, 将来自有好处。 Xiànzài duō yònggōng, jiānglái zì yǒu hǎochu. You will certainly benefit in the future from hard study now. 这电影部分情节自属有趣, 但终非佳片。 Zhè diànyǐng bùfen qíngjié zì shǔ yǒuqù, dàn zhōng fēi jiā piàn. Of course parts of the story are fun, but it’s not really a good film. 
preposition from; since 自远而近 zìyuǎn&apos;érjìn from far to near; approach; come closer 自左而右 zì zuǒ ér yòu from left to right 自即日起生效 Zì jírì qǐ shēngxiào become effective (as) from this date; with effect from (w.e.f.) this date 自数十元至几千元不等 zì shù shí yuán zhì jǐqiān yuán bùděng range from tens to thousands of yuan 他自小在这儿长大。 Tā zì xiǎo zài zhèr zhǎngdà. He was brought up here. or He grew up here. 本次列车自北京开往南京。 Běn cì lièchē zì Běijīng kāi wǎng Nánjīng. This train runs from Beijing to Nanjing.</defn>
            </entry>
            <dictref dictid="PACE" entryid="36848128"/>
            <catassign category="100/Freq50"/>
        </card>
        <card language="chinese">
            <entry>
                <headword charset="sc">后</headword>
                <headword charset="tc">后</headword>
                <pron type="hypy" tones="numbers">hou4</pron>
                <defn>noun 1 empress; queen 2 emperor; monarch sovereign 夏后 xiàhòu emperor of the Xia Dynasty</defn>
            </entry>
            <dictref dictid="PACE" entryid="22717184"/>
            <catassign category="100/Freq50"/>
        </card>
        <card language="chinese">
            <entry>
                <headword charset="sc">作</headword>
                <headword charset="tc">作</headword>
                <pron type="hypy" tones="numbers">zuo4</pron>
                <defn>noun writings; work 新作 xīnzuò a new work 成功之作 chénggōng zhī zuò a successful work 
verb 1 rise; grow 枪声大作。 Qiāngshēng dàzuò. Heavy firing broke out. 2 write; compose 作画 zuòhuà paint a picture 作诗 zuòshī compose a poem 作书一封 zuò shū yī fēng write a letter 3 pretend; affect 故作怒容 gù zuò nùróng pretend to be angry 4 regard as; take sb. or sth. for 看作 kànzuò look upon as; regard as See 37143552作废zuo4fei4作废 5 feel; have See 37151488作呕zuo4ou3作呕 6 engage in an activity See 37150976作孽zuo4nie4作孽</defn>
            </entry>
            <dictref dictid="PACE" entryid="37138944"/>
            <catassign category="100/Freq50"/>
        </card>
        <card language="chinese">
            <entry>
                <headword charset="sc">里</headword>
                <headword charset="tc">裏</headword>
                <pron type="hypy" tones="numbers">li3</pron>
                <defn>noun 1 lining; inside (of clothing) 衣服里 yīfu lǐ lining (of a garment) 被里 bèilǐ inside of a quilt 这面是里儿, 那面是面儿。 Zhè miàn shì lǐr, nà miàn shì miànr. This is the inside, that is the outside. 2 inner (opp. 外) 圈里人 quān lǐ rén insider; member of the inner circle</defn>
            </entry>
            <dictref dictid="PACE" entryid="25604352"/>
            <catassign category="100/Freq60"/>
        </card>
        <card language="chinese">
            <entry>
                <headword charset="sc">道</headword>
                <headword charset="tc">道</headword>
                <pron type="hypy" tones="numbers">dao4</pron>
                <defn>1 road 2 path M: 条tiáo [条] / 股gǔ [股] 3 principle 4 truth 5 morality 6 reason 7 skill 8 method 9 Dao (of Daoism) 10 to say 11 to speak 12 to talk 13 classifier for long thin things (rivers, cracks etc), barriers (walls, doors etc), questions (in an exam etc), commands, courses in a meal, steps in a process 14 (old) circuit (administrative division)</defn>
            </entry>
            <dictref dictid="PCED" entryid="16690176"/>
            <catassign category="100/Freq60"/>
        </card>
        <card language="chinese">
            <entry>
                <headword charset="sc">然</headword>
                <headword charset="tc">然</headword>
                <pron type="hypy" tones="numbers">ran2</pron>
                <defn>1 correct 2 right 3 so 4 thus 5 like this 6 -ly</defn>
            </entry>
            <dictref dictid="PCED" entryid="10824960"/>
            <catassign category="100/Freq60"/>
        </card>
        <card language="chinese">
            <entry>
                <headword charset="sc">家</headword>
                <headword charset="tc">傢</headword>
                <pron type="hypy" tones="numbers">jia1</pron>
                <defn>see 家伙jiāhuo [家伙]</defn>
            </entry>
            <dictref dictid="PCED" entryid="36982784"/>
            <catassign category="100/Freq60"/>
        </card>
        <card language="chinese">
            <entry>
                <headword charset="sc">事</headword>
                <headword charset="tc">事</headword>
                <pron type="hypy" tones="numbers">shi4</pron>
                <defn>1 matter 2 thing 3 item 4 work 5 affair M: 件jiàn [件] / 桩zhuāng [桩] / 回huí [回]</defn>
            </entry>
            <dictref dictid="PCED" entryid="719360"/>
            <catassign category="100/Freq60"/>
        </card>
        <card language="chinese">
            <entry>
                <headword charset="sc">成</headword>
                <headword charset="tc">成</headword>
                <pron type="hypy" tones="numbers">cheng2</pron>
                <defn>1 to succeed 2 to finish 3 to complete 4 to accomplish 5 to become 6 to turn into 7 to be all right 8 OK! 9 one tenth</defn>
            </entry>
            <dictref dictid="PCED" entryid="6836480"/>
            <catassign category="100/Freq60"/>
        </card>
        <card language="chinese">
            <entry>
                <headword charset="sc">经</headword>
                <headword charset="tc">經</headword>
                <pron type="hypy" tones="numbers">jing1</pron>
                <defn>noun 1 textile warp (opp. 纬) 2 Chinese medicine channels 3 geography longitude (opp. 纬) 东经 dōngjīng east longitude 西经 xījīng west longitude 4 scripture; sutra; canon; classic 《孝经》 《Xiàojīng》 The Classic of Filial Piety 《金刚经》 《Jīngāngjīng》 The Diamond Sutra 5 menses; menstruation 6 (Jīng) a surname 
verb 1 literary manage; deal in; engage in 经国之策 jīng guó zhī cè a plan to govern the country 2 hang oneself See 36870400自经zi4jing1自经 
adjective constant; regular 荒诞不经 huāngdànbùjīng preposterous; absurd 
verb 1 pass through; undergo; experience 经卡拉奇回国 Jīng kǎ lā qí huíguó return home via (or by way of) Karachi 赴沪途中经宁而未停留。 Fù Hù túzhōng jīng nìng ér wèi tíngliú. I passed through Nanjing on my way to Shanghai, but I didn’t stop over. 我这辈子可经了不少事。 Wǒ zhè bèizi kě jīng le bùshǎo shì. I have seen quite a lot in my life. 2 stand; bear; endure 经不起诱惑 jīng bùqǐ yòuhuò cannot withstand the temptations 经得起时间的考验 Jīngdeqǐ shíjiān de kǎoyàn stand the test of time 
preposition as a result of; after; through 经商定 jīng shāngdìng after consultation the decision was made 经某人建议 jīng mǒurén jiànyì upon sb.’s proposal 经检查, 产品质量合格。 Jīng jiǎnchá, chǎnpǐn zhìliàng hégé. Examination confirmed product quality was up to standard.</defn>
            </entry>
            <dictref dictid="PACE" entryid="24355584"/>
            <catassign category="100/Freq70"/>
        </card>
        <card language="chinese">
            <entry>
                <headword charset="sc">么</headword>
                <headword charset="tc">麼</headword>
                <pron type="hypy" tones="numbers">me5</pron>
                <defn>affix [suffix used in interogatives, pronouns and adverbs] 
affix [a syllable inserted in a line of a song for balance] 五月的花儿红呀么红似火。 Wǔyuè de huā&apos;ér hóng ya me hóng sì huǒ. Red as fire are the flowers that bloom in May.</defn>
            </entry>
            <dictref dictid="PACE" entryid="26605568"/>
            <catassign category="100/Freq70"/>
        </card>
        <card language="chinese">
            <entry>
                <headword charset="sc">法</headword>
                <headword charset="tc">法</headword>
                <pron type="hypy" tones="numbers">fa3</pron>
                <defn>1 law 2 method 3 way 4 Buddhist teaching 5 Legalist</defn>
            </entry>
            <dictref dictid="PCED" entryid="9879040"/>
            <catassign category="100/Freq70"/>
        </card>
        <card language="chinese">
            <entry>
                <headword charset="sc">学</headword>
                <headword charset="tc">學</headword>
                <pron type="hypy" tones="numbers">xue2</pron>
                <defn>1 to learn 2 to study 3 to imitate 4 science 5 -ology</defn>
            </entry>
            <dictref dictid="PCED" entryid="4989696"/>
            <catassign category="100/Freq70"/>
        </card>
        <card language="chinese">
            <entry>
                <headword charset="sc">同</headword>
                <headword charset="tc">同</headword>
                <pron type="hypy" tones="numbers">tong2</pron>
                <defn>verb be the same as “鎚”同“锤”。 “chuí”tóng“chuí”. 鎚 is the same as 锤。 
adjective same; alike; similar 同年级 tóng niánjí in the same grade 
adverb together; in common 和工人同吃同住同劳动 Hé gōngrén tóng chī tóng zhù tóng láodòng eat, live, and work with the workers; live with the workers, eat the same food, and join them in physical labour 我们两国同属第三世界。 Wǒmen liǎng guó tóng shǔ dì-sān shìjiè. Both our countries belong to the Third World. 
preposition 1 [indicating company, relationship, involvement, etc.] with 我同你一起去。 Wǒ tóng nǐ yīqǐ qù. I’ll go with you. 这同你没有关系。 Zhè tóng nǐ méiyǒu guānxi. This has nothing to do with you. 这件事同他有牵连。 Zhè jiàn shì tóng tā yǒu qiānlián. He is implicated in the affair. 2 [introducing the recipient of an action] 他同我商量下一步该怎么办。 Tā tóng wǒ shāngliang xià yī bù gāi zěnme bàn. He consulted me about what to do next. 他上午来同我告别。 tā shàngwǔ lái tóng wǒ gàobié. He came to say good-bye to me this morning. 3 [showing comparison] like; in relation to 同去年相比, 产量增加了20%。 tóng qùnián xiāngbǐ, chǎnliàng zēngjiā le 20%. Output has increased by 20% over last year. 湖面同明镜一样清澈。 Húmiàn tóng míngjìng yīyàng qīngchè. The limpid lake is like a mirror. 4 dialect for 别着急, 我同你想个办法。 Bié zháojí, wǒ tóng nǐ xiǎng ge bànfǎ. Don’t worry, I’ll find you a way out. 这封信我一直同你保存着。 Zhè fēng xìn wǒ yīzhí tóng nǐ bǎocúnzhe. I’ve kept this letter for you all this time. 
conjunction and 老师同学生 Lǎoshī tóng xuésheng teachers and students</defn>
            </entry>
            <dictref dictid="PACE" entryid="31604224"/>
            <catassign category="100/Freq70"/>
        </card>
        <card language="chinese">
            <entry>
                <headword charset="sc">如</headword>
                <headword charset="tc">如</headword>
                <pron type="hypy" tones="numbers">ru2</pron>
                <defn>verb 1 be in compliance (or accordance) with 这才如了大伙的意。 Zhè cái rú le dà huǒ de yì. Finally everybody was satisfied. 2 like; as; as if 如你所说 rú nǐ suǒ shuō as you’ve said 如离弦之箭 rú lí xián zhī jiàn like an arrow discharged from a bow 十年如一日 shí nián rú yī rì persevere for ten years as if it were one day 湖水如镜。 Húshuǐ rú jìng. The lake is like a mirror. 事情并不如他们所想的那样简单。 Shìqing bìng bù rú tāmen suǒ xiǎng de nàyàng jiǎndān. Things aren’t as simple as they think. 3 [usu. in the negative] can compare with; be as good as 不如 bùrú not equal to; not as good as; inferior to 4 surpass; exceed 光景一年强如一年。 Guāngjǐng yī nián qiáng rú yī nián. The situation is getting better year by year. 5 for instance; such as; as 唐朝有很多大诗人, 如李白, 杜甫, 白居易等。 Tángcháo yǒu hěn duō dà shīrén, rú Lǐ Bó, Dù Fǔ, Bái Jūyì děng. The Tang Dynasty produced a host of great poets, such as Li Bai, Du Fu, and Bai Juyi. 6 literary go to 如厕 rúcè go to the toilet 
preposition according to 如约前往 Rúyuē qiánwǎng go as one has promised 
conjunction if; in case (of); in the event of; as if; as though 如有火警, 将玻璃击碎。 Rú yǒu huǒjǐng, jiāng bōli jī suì. In case of fire, break the glass. [a notice] 如处理得当, 问题不难解决。 Rú chǔlǐ dédàng, wèntí bù nán jiějué. The problem will not be difficult to solve if properly handled. 如发生此种情况, 我们即诉诸法律。 Rú fāshēng cǐ zhǒng qíngkuàng, wǒmen jí sùzhū fǎlǜ. In that event, we would take the matter to court. 
affix classical [as an adjective suffix] 侃侃如也 Kǎnkǎn rú yě fervently eloquent</defn>
            </entry>
            <dictref dictid="PACE" entryid="29157120"/>
            <catassign category="100/Freq70"/>
        </card>
        <card language="chinese">
            <entry>
                <headword charset="sc">现</headword>
                <headword charset="tc">現</headword>
                <pron type="hypy" tones="numbers">xian4</pron>
                <defn>noun cash; ready money 付现 fùxiàn pay cash 
verb show; appear; become visible 现原形 xiàn yuánxíng show one’s true colours 她脸上现出一丝笑容。 Tā liǎnshàng xiànchū yī sī xiàoróng. A faint smile appeared on (or crept over) her face. 
adjective 1 present; current; existing 现况 xiànkuàng the existing (or present) situation 现阶段 xiànjiēduàn present stage 2 (of money, etc.) on hand See 32961024现钱xian4qian2现钱 
adverb recent; improvise; extempore 现烙的烧饼 xiàn lào de shāobing sesame buns just out of the oven 现派张先生前往你处接洽。 xiàn pài zhāng xiānsheng qiánwǎng nǐ chù jiēqià. We are now sending Mr Zhang to contact you. 他在晚会上现编了一首诗。 Tā zài wǎnhuì shàng xiàn biān le yī shǒu shī. He improvised a poem at the evening party. 这点儿技术也是工作中现学的。 Zhèdiǎnr jìshù yěshì gōngzuò zhōng xiàn xué de. Whatever skills I have were picked up on the job.</defn>
            </entry>
            <dictref dictid="PACE" entryid="32954624"/>
            <catassign category="100/Freq80"/>
        </card>
        <card language="chinese">
            <entry>
                <headword charset="sc">动</headword>
                <headword charset="tc">動</headword>
                <pron type="hypy" tones="numbers">dong4</pron>
                <defn>verb 1 move; stir 他扭了腰, 动不了了。 Tā niǔ le yāo, dòng bù liǎoliǎo. He’s strained his back and can’t move. 微风吹动树叶。 Wēifēng chuīdòng shùyè. A breeze stirred the leaves. 这东西一个人拿不动。 Zhè dōngxi yī ge rén ná bù dòng. No one can carry that single-handed. or That’s too heavy for one person. 2 act; get moving 经过动员, 群众普遍动起来了。 Jīngguò dòngyuán, qúnzhòng pǔbiàn dòng qǐlai le. After being encouraged to action everyone got involved. 3 change; alter 这句话只要动一两个字就顺了。 Zhè jù huà zhǐ yào dòng yī liǎng ge zì jiù shùn le. Just change one or two words and the sentence will read smoothly. 4 use 动脑子 dòng nǎozi use one’s head 5 touch (one&apos;s heart); arouse 动感情 dòng gǎnqíng be carried away by emotion; get worked up; be moved 动了公愤 dòng le gōngfèn arouse public indignation 不为甜言蜜语所动 bù wéi tiányánmìyǔ suǒ dòng not swayed by fine words 6 dialect [usu. in the negative] eat or drink 不动荤腥 bù dòng hūnxīng never touch meat or fish; be a vegetarian 
adverb literary easily; frequently 影片一经上演, 观众动以万计。 Yǐngpiàn yījīng shàngyǎn, guānzhòng dòng yǐ wàn jì. Immediately on release, the film drew an audience of thousands.</defn>
            </entry>
            <dictref dictid="PACE" entryid="20201728"/>
            <catassign category="100/Freq80"/>
        </card>
        <card language="chinese">
            <entry>
                <headword charset="sc">面</headword>
                <headword charset="tc">面</headword>
                <pron type="hypy" tones="numbers">mian4</pron>
                <defn>noun 1 face 面带笑容 miàndài xiàoróng with a smile on one’s face 面无惧色 miàn wú jùsè look dauntless; fearless look 2 surface; top; face 钟面 zhōngmiàn clock face; dial 面儿磨得很光。 Miànr mó de hěn guāng. The surface has been polished shiny bright. 3 side 这种纸一面光。 Zhèzhǒng zhǐ yī miàn guāng. This kind of paper is smooth on one side. 这本书有多少面？ Zhè běn shū yǒu duōshao miàn？ How many pages are there in this book? 4 right side; cover; outside 书面儿 shūmiànr cover of a book 夹袄的面儿 jiá&apos;ǎo de miànr outer shell of a lined jacket 这块布做里儿, 那块布做面儿。 Zhè kuài bù zuò lǐr, nà kuài bù zuò miànr. Use this piece of cloth for the lining and that piece for the outside. 5 mathematics surface 立方体有六个面。 Lìfāngtǐ yǒu liù ge miàn. A cube has six surfaces. 6 overall; entire area (as opposed to individual points) 部长下去蹲点儿了, 面上的工作他让我来抓。 Bùzhǎng xiàqu dūndiǎnr le, miàn shàng de gōngzuò tā ràng wǒ lái zhuā. The minister has gone to spend time in a grass-roots unit and left me in charge of overall business. 7 extent; range; scale; scope 知识面广 Zhīshi miàn guǎng have a wide range of knowledge 知识面窄 Zhīshimiàn zhǎi have a narrow range of knowledge 这次讨论涉及的面很广。 Zhè cì tǎolùn shèjí de miàn hěn guǎng. The discussion covered a wide range of topics. 8 face; feelings 看在我的面上, 饶了他这一回吧。 Kàn zài wǒ de miàn shàng, ráo le tā zhè yī huí ba. Please let him off this time for my sake. 
verb 1 meet; come out See 66915299面市mian4shi4面市 2 face (a certain direction) 这房子面南坐北。 Zhè fángzi miàn nán zuò běi. The house faces south. 
measure word 1 [for flat things] 一面镜子 yī miàn jìngzi a mirror 两面旗子 liǎng miàn qízi two flags 2 [for the number of times people meet each other] 我们只见过一面。 wǒmen zhǐjiàn guò yī miàn. We have only met once. 
affix [suffix for location or direction] 前面 qiánmiàn in front; at the head; ahead 外面 wàimiàn outside; out 
adverb directly; face-to-face 面告 miàngào tell sb. personally</defn>
            </entry>
            <dictref dictid="PACE" entryid="26810368"/>
            <catassign category="100/Freq80"/>
        </card>
        <card language="chinese">
            <entry>
                <headword charset="sc">起</headword>
                <headword charset="tc">起</headword>
                <pron type="hypy" tones="numbers">qi3</pron>
                <defn>verb 1 rise; get up; stand up 起席 qǐxí rise from the table 早睡早起 zǎoshuìzǎoqǐ early to bed and early to rise 2 remove; extract; pull 起雷 qǐléi clear mines 起油 qǐyóu remove grease stains 起钉子 qǐ dīngzi draw out a nail 起瓶塞 qǐ píngsāi pull the cork from a bottle 把画起下来 bǎ huà qǐ xiàlai take down a picture 3 appear; raise 脚上起水泡 jiǎo shàng qǐ shuǐpào get blisters on one’s feet 4 rise; grow 起疑心 qǐ yíxīn become suspicious 起作用 qǐ zuòyòng take effect 起风了。 Qǐ fēng le. The wind is rising. 5 draft; work out 起稿子 qǐ gǎozi work out (or make) a draft 6 build; set up 起伙 qǐ huǒ set up a mess 起一堵墙 qǐ yī dǔ qiáng build a wall 7 start; begin 从今天起 cóng jīntiān qǐ starting from today 8 draw; get 起护照 qǐ hùzhào get one’s passport 9 leave; start See 28173312起程qi3cheng2起程;28176896起飞qi3fei1 起飞 10 move (or rise) up 这球不起了。 Zhè qiú bù qǐ le. There is no spring left in this ball. or The ball doesn’t bounce. 11 to start; to launch See 28171776起兵qi3bing1起兵;28188160起事qi3shi4 起事 
preposition 1 [after a verb preceded by 从 or 由] 从头儿讲起 cóng tóu&apos;ér jiǎng qǐ tell the story from the very beginning 从何说起？ Cóng hé shuō qǐ？ What shall I say? or What’s there to say? 2 dialect from 起这儿往北 qǐ zhèr wǎng běi go north from here 3 dialect by 我见他起窗外走过。 Wǒ jiàn tā qǐ chuāngwài zǒuguò. I saw him going by the window. 
noun (Qǐ) a surname 
measure word 1 case; instance 一起交通事故 Yī qǐ jiāotōng shìgù a traffic accident 两起大脑炎 Liǎng qǐ dànǎoyán two cases of cerebritis 2 batch; group 分两起出发 fēn liǎng qǐ chūfā set out in two groups (or batches)</defn>
            </entry>
            <dictref dictid="PACE" entryid="28169984"/>
            <catassign category="100/Freq80"/>
        </card>
        <card language="chinese">
            <entry>
                <headword charset="sc">定</headword>
                <headword charset="tc">定</headword>
                <pron type="hypy" tones="numbers">ding4</pron>
                <defn>verb 1 decide; fix; set 定方针 Dìng fāngzhēn decide on a policy 定计划 dìng jìhuà make a plan 开会时间定在明天上午。 Kāihuì shíjiān dìng zài míngtiān shàngwǔ. The meeting is fixed for tomorrow morning. 代表团定于今日离京。 Dàibiǎotuán dìngyú jīnrì lí jīng. The delegation is due to leave Beijing today. 2 subscribe to (a newspaper, etc.); book (seats, tickets, hotel rooms, etc.); order (merchandise, etc.) 
adjective 1 calm; stable 天下大定。 Tiānxià dà dìng. The country is generally calm. 2 fixed; settled; established See 20153600定见ding4jian4定见 
adverb literary surely; certainly; definitely 定可取胜 dìng kě qǔshèng be sure to win; victory is certain; sure to prevail</defn>
            </entry>
            <dictref dictid="PACE" entryid="20147200"/>
            <catassign category="100/Freq80"/>
        </card>
        <card language="chinese">
            <entry>
                <headword charset="sc">天</headword>
                <headword charset="tc">天</headword>
                <pron type="hypy" tones="numbers">tian1</pron>
                <defn>1 day 2 sky 3 heaven</defn>
            </entry>
            <dictref dictid="PCED" entryid="4536576"/>
            <catassign category="100/Freq80"/>
        </card>
        <card language="chinese">
            <entry>
                <headword charset="sc">还</headword>
                <headword charset="tc">還</headword>
                <pron type="hypy" tones="numbers">hai2</pron>
                <defn>adverb 1 still; yet 还有一些具体问题要解决。 Háiyǒu yīxiē jùtǐ wèntí yào jiějué. Some specific problems have yet to be solved. 我们还没有开始。 Wǒmen hái méiyǒu kāishǐ. We haven’t started yet. 夜深了, 他还在学习。 Yèshēn le, tā hái zài xuéxí. It was late at night and he was still studying. 2 even more; still more 今年的收成比去年还要好。 Jīnnián de shōucheng bǐ qùnián hái yào hǎo. This year’s harvest is even better than last year’s. 3 as well; in addition 我们不但要提高产量, 还要保证质量。 Wǒmen bùdàn yào tígāo chǎnliàng, hái yào bǎozhèng zhìliàng. We want not only to increase the quantity of products, but also to ensure the quality. 这本书我还想看一遍。 Zhè běn shū wǒ hái xiǎng kàn yī biàn. I want to read the book once more. 4 passably; fairly 屋子不大, 收拾得倒还干净。 Wūzi bùdà, shōushi de dào hái gānjìng. The room is small, but it’s kept quite tidy. 这张画儿画得还可以。 Zhè zhāng huàr huà de hái kěyǐ. The painting wasn’t done too badly. or This painting’s not very bad. 5 as early as 还在三年前他们就认识了。 hái zài sān niánqián tāmen jiù rènshi le. They got to know each other three years ago. 他还在读中学时就开始写小说。 Tā hái zài dú zhōngxué shí jiù kāishǐ xiě xiǎoshuō. He started to write novels when he was in middle school. 6 even 你跑那么快还赶不上他, 何况我呢？ Nǐ pǎo nàme kuài hái gǎnbùshàng tā, hékuàng wǒ ne? Even a good runner like you can’t catch up with him, how can I? 7 [for emphasis] 那还用说！ Nà hái yòng shuō! That goes without saying. 这还了得！ Zhè hái liǎode! This is the limit! or This is simply atrocious! 8 [expressing realization or discovery] 他还真有办法。 Tā hái zhēn yǒu bànfǎ. You’ve got to admit he’s resourceful. or He really is resourceful. 下这么大的雨, 没想到你还真准时到了。 Xià zhème dà de yǔ, méi xiǎngdào nǐ hái zhēn zhǔnshí dàoliǎo. I didn’t expect you’d arrive on time as it’s raining so hard.</defn>
            </entry>
            <dictref dictid="PACE" entryid="22249984"/>
            <catassign category="100/Freq90"/>
        </card>
        <card language="chinese">
            <entry>
                <headword charset="sc">部</headword>
                <headword charset="tc">部</headword>
                <pron type="hypy" tones="numbers">bu4</pron>
                <defn>noun 1 part; section 南部 nánbù the southern part 上部 shàngbù upper part 分为三部 Fēnwéi sān bù divide into three parts (or sections) 2 unit; ministry; department; board 解放军某部 jiěfàngjūn mǒu bù a PLA unit 3 headquarters 连部 liánbù company headquarters 4 troops; forces 率部突围 shuàibù tūwéi lead the troops to break through an encirclement 
measure word 1 [for books, films, etc.] 两部字典 liǎng bù zìdiǎn two dictionaries 一部电影 yī bù diànyǐng a film 2 [for machines and vehicles] 两部汽车 liǎng bù qìchē two cars 一部机器 yī bù jīqì a machine 
verb literary command; lead 部领 bù lǐng command</defn>
            </entry>
            <dictref dictid="PACE" entryid="18044416"/>
            <catassign category="100/Freq90"/>
        </card>
        <card language="chinese">
            <entry>
                <headword charset="sc">其</headword>
                <headword charset="tc">其</headword>
                <pron type="hypy" tones="numbers">qi2</pron>
                <defn>literary pronoun 1 his (her, its, their) 其父 Qí fù his (or her) father 《战国策》取其灵快。 《Zhàn Guócè》 qǔ qí líng kuài. Intrigues of the Warring States is noted for its agility of thought and expressiveness of style. 2 he (she, it, they) 劝其戒烟 Quàn qí jièyān advise him (or her) to give up smoking 促其早日实现 cù qí zǎorì shíxiàn help bring it about at an early date 3 that; such 正当其时 zhèngdāng qíshí just at that time; at the opportune moment 查无其事。 Chá wú qí shì. Investigation shows that nothing of this sort has happened. 4 [referring to no definite person or thing] it 大请其客 Dà qǐng qí kè invite many guests to dinner; entertain lavishly 忘其所以 wàngqísuǒyǐ forget all else 
noun (Qí) a surname 
auxiliary classical 1 [making a guess or a retort] 其奈我何？ Qínàiwǒhé？ What can they do to me? 2 [giving an order] 子其勉之！ Zǐ qí miǎn zhī! Exert yourself to the utmost! 
affix [after an adverb] 极其 jíqí extremely 尤其 yóuqí in particular</defn>
            </entry>
            <dictref dictid="PACE" entryid="28110592"/>
            <catassign category="100/Freq90"/>
        </card>
        <card language="chinese">
            <entry>
                <headword charset="sc">主</headword>
                <headword charset="tc">主</headword>
                <pron type="hypy" tones="numbers">zhu3</pron>
                <defn>noun 1 host (opp. 客, 宾) 宾主 bīnzhǔ host and guest 2 owner; master (opp. 仆) 主仆 zhǔ-pú master and servant 企业主 qǐyè zhǔ proprietor of an enterprise; business owner 3 person or party concerned 买主 mǎizhǔ buyer; customer 事主 shìzhǔ victim of a crime 4 Christianity God; Lord 5 Islam Allah 6 definite view; decision 我一时心里没主。 Wǒ yīshí xīnli méi zhǔ. For a moment, I just didn’t know what to do. 7 spirit (or memorial) tablet 神主 shénzhǔ ancestral tablet 
verb 1 manage; direct; in charge of See 36559616主管zhu3guan3主管 2 indicate; signify 早霞主雨, 晚霞主晴。 Zǎo xiá zhǔ yǔ, wǎnxiá zhǔ qíng. Rosy morning clouds indicate rain, and a rosy sunset means fine weather. 3 advocate; decide 力主和平 Lì zhǔ hépíng advocate strongly for peace 
adjective 1 main; primary (opp. 副) 主航道 zhǔhángdào main (or principal) channel 2 of oneself; on one&apos;s own will See 36553728主动zhu3dong4主动;36558592主观zhu3guan1主观</defn>
            </entry>
            <dictref dictid="PACE" entryid="36549120"/>
            <catassign category="100/Freq90"/>
        </card>
        <card language="chinese">
            <entry>
                <headword charset="sc">样</headword>
                <headword charset="tc">樣</headword>
                <pron type="hypy" tones="numbers">yang4</pron>
                <defn>noun 1 appearance; shape; look; form 这两支笔样儿差不多, 色儿不一样。 Zhè liǎng zhī bǐ yàngr chàbuduō, sèr bù yīyàng. These two pens are alike except that they’re different colours. 2 manner; air; appearance 几年没见, 他还是那个样儿。 Jǐ nián méi jiàn, tā háishi nà ge yàngr. It’s years since I last saw him, but he still looks the same. 3 sample; model; pattern 鞋样 xiéyàng shoe pattern; outline of a shoe’s upper and sole 4 tendency; likelihood 看样儿要下雨了。 kàn yàng r yào xiàyǔ le. It looks like rain. 
measure word kind; type 三样点心 Sān yàng diǎnxin three kinds of pastries 商店虽小, 各样货物俱全。 Shāngdiàn suī xiǎo, gèyàng huòwù jùquán. Small as it is, the shop stocks all kinds of wares.</defn>
            </entry>
            <dictref dictid="PACE" entryid="34187008"/>
            <catassign category="100/Freq90"/>
        </card>
        <card language="chinese">
            <entry>
                <headword charset="sc">理</headword>
                <headword charset="tc">理</headword>
                <pron type="hypy" tones="numbers">li3</pron>
                <defn>noun 1 texture; grain (in wood, skin, etc.) 木理 mùlǐ grain of wood 2 order; sequence 条理 tiáolǐ orderliness; proper arrangement 3 reason; logic; truth 讲理 jiǎnglǐ listen to reason; talk sense 没理 méilǐ be unreasonable 有理 yǒulǐ be on the right 不讲理 bù jiǎnglǐ lose all reason; be not amenable to reason 他讲得在理。 tā jiǎng de zài lǐ. There is truth in what he says. 4 natural science (esp. physics) 理学院 lǐxuéyuàn college of science 文理兼通 Wén lǐ jiāntōng be knowledgeable in both arts and sciences 
verb 1 manage; run 有要事待理 yǒu yàoshì dài lǐ have important business to attend to 2 put in order; tidy up 理出头绪 lǐchū tóuxù straighten a matter out 把书理一下。 bǎ shū lǐ yīxià. Put the books in order. 把房间理一理。 Bǎ fángjiān lǐ yī lǐ. Straighten up the room. 3 [usu. in the negative] pay attention to; make a gesture or speak to 不理 bùlǐ take no notice of; pay no attention to 谁也不理谁 Shuí yě bù lǐ shuí be not on speaking terms 他想跟我讲话, 我没理他。 Tā xiǎng gēn wǒ jiǎnghuà, wǒ méi lǐ tā. I ignored him when he tried to talk to me.</defn>
            </entry>
            <dictref dictid="PACE" entryid="25615616"/>
            <catassign category="100/Freq90"/>
        </card>
        <card language="chinese">
            <entry>
                <headword charset="sc">心</headword>
                <headword charset="tc">心</headword>
                <pron type="hypy" tones="numbers">xin1</pron>
                <defn>noun 1 heart 2 heart; mind; feeling; intention 伤人的心 shāng rén de xīn wound (or hurt) sb.’s feelings 羞耻之心 xiūchǐzhīxīn sense of shame 你的心是好的, 但事情办得不好。 Nǐ dexīn shì hǎo de, dàn shìqing bàn de bù hǎo. You meant well but you didn’t handle the job well. 他人在这儿, 但心不在。 Tārén zài zhèr, dàn xīn bùzài. He himself is here, but his thoughts are elsewhere. 3 centre; core 江心 jiāngxīn the middle of a river; halfway across the river 白菜心 Báicài xīn the heart of a Chinese cabbage 4 archaic astronomy xin (the fifth of the twenty-eight constellations (二十八宿) into which the celestial sphere was divided, consisting of three stars in Scorpio)</defn>
            </entry>
            <dictref dictid="PACE" entryid="33333504"/>
            <catassign category="100/Freq100"/>
        </card>
        <card language="chinese">
            <entry>
                <headword charset="sc">前</headword>
                <headword charset="tc">前</headword>
                <pron type="hypy" tones="numbers">qian2</pron>
                <defn>noun 1 front (opp. 后) 前院 qiányuàn front courtyard 楼前 lóu qián in front of the building 将军胸前戴着所有的勋章。 Jiāngjun xiōngqián dàizhe suǒyǒu de xūnzhāng. The general was wearing all his medals on his chest. 2 future See 28323072前程qian2cheng2前程 3 ago; before (opp. 后) 晚饭前 Wǎn fànqián before supper 这个故事发生在五百年前。 Zhège gùshi fāshēng zài wǔbǎi nián qián. The story took place 500 years ago. 4 forward; ahead (opp. 后) 朝前走 Cháo qián zǒu go straight ahead 往前看 wǎng qián kàn look forward 5 preceding 前一阶段 qián yī jiēduàn the preceding stage 前资本主义 qián zīběnzhǔyì precapitalism 6 former; formerly 前任校长 Qiánrèn xiàozhǎng former principal (of a school) 7 first (opp. 后) 前五排 qián wǔ pái the first five rows 这次比赛的前三名 Zhècì bǐsài de qián sān míng the first three places in this competition 8 front; battlefield 支前 zhīqián support the front 9 (Qián) a surname 
verb move forward; go (straight) ahead 勇往直前 yǒngwǎngzhíqián forge ahead bravely</defn>
            </entry>
            <dictref dictid="PACE" entryid="28318720"/>
            <catassign category="100/Freq100"/>
        </card>
        <card language="chinese">
            <entry>
                <headword charset="sc">但</headword>
                <headword charset="tc">但</headword>
                <pron type="hypy" tones="numbers">dan4</pron>
                <defn>conjunction but; yet; still; nevertheless 这消息可能出乎意料, 但却是真实的。 Zhè xiāoxi kěnéng chūhū yìliào, dàn què shì zhēnshí de. The news may be unexpected; nevertheless, it is true. 
adverb only; merely 明哲保身, 但求无过。 míngzhébǎoshēn, dànqiúwúguò Being worldly-wise, play safe and seek only to avoid blame.</defn>
            </entry>
            <dictref dictid="PACE" entryid="19614208"/>
            <catassign category="100/Freq100"/>
        </card>
        <card language="chinese">
            <entry>
                <headword charset="sc">因</headword>
                <headword charset="tc">因</headword>
                <pron type="hypy" tones="numbers">yin1</pron>
                <defn>noun cause; reason (opp. 果) 起因 qǐyīn cause; origin 必有他因 bì yǒu tā yīn there must be some other reason 
verb literary 1 follow; carry on See 34679040因袭yin1xi2因袭 2 conform to; accord with 因病下药 yīnbìngxiàyào suit the medicine to the illness 因其自然 yīn qí zìrán let things take their natural course 
preposition because of; as a result of 因病请假 yīn bìng qǐngjià ask for sick leave 因公死亡 yīngōng sǐwáng work-related death 因公牺牲 yīngōng xīshēng die while on duty; die at one’s post 会议因故延期。 Huìyì yīngù yánqī. The meeting has been postponed for some reason. 
conjunction because 他因有其他事情未能出席。 Tā yīn yǒu qítā shìqing wèinéng chūxí. He was absent because he had other things to attend to.</defn>
            </entry>
            <dictref dictid="PACE" entryid="34672384"/>
            <catassign category="100/Freq100"/>
        </card>
        <card language="chinese">
            <entry>
                <headword charset="sc">实</headword>
                <headword charset="tc">實</headword>
                <pron type="hypy" tones="numbers">shi2</pron>
                <defn>noun 1 reality; fact 名不副实 míngbùfùshí the name falls short of the reality; more in name than in reality; not live up to its name 2 fruit; seed 开花结实 Kāihuā jiēshí blossom and bear fruit 
adjective 1 solid 地基要砸实。 Dìjī yào zá shí. The foundations must be tamped solid. 里面是实的。 Lǐmiàn shì shí de. It’s solid. 2 true; real; actual (opp. 虚) See 70593763实利shi2li4实利 
adverb literary really; truly 实感悲伤 shí gǎn bēishāng feel really sad</defn>
            </entry>
            <dictref dictid="PACE" entryid="30089728"/>
            <catassign category="100/Freq100"/>
        </card>
    </cards>
</plecoflash>